<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<data>
	<post>
		<ID>1482</ID>
		<Title>Inside Outside</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>As architects and designers, we often blur the line between indoor and outdoor spaces. It isn’t hard to do so in our Los Angeles office when one of the benefits of living in California is getting to spend so much time outdoors all year long – the exterior space is just as important as the interior. <em>Inside Outside</em> is our platform for transparency - a place where our team members are front and center. We are more than just the projects we plan and design – we are creative thinkers, technical experts, designers, makers, communicators, collaborators, artists, visionaries, and a mix of cultures from all over the globe.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1760,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/FFP.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1760"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1761,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/DesertX_FIX.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1761"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2018-04-04 13:24:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1484</ID>
		<Title>Architect Frederick Fisher: Building a lasting legacy in the L.A. art world</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Frederick Fisher is something of an invisible man among L.A. architects: He creates buildings that are acclaimed by their users but have often gone unnoticed by the world at large. His houses, academic buildings and spaces for making and showing art are all about substance rather than show. Well-proportioned rooms, natural lighting and finely detailed materials enrich one's experience in a subliminal way. So subtle is the architecture, so elusive in the camera's eye, that the forty-year career of Fisher and his longtime partners, Joe Coriaty and David Ross, is less celebrated than it deserves to be.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>That's likely to change in the next few years, for the 30-person office has four major Los Angeles projects in development. A glass wing will open up the Natural History Museum to Exposition Park and its new neighbor, the swoopy silver spaceship of the Lucas Museum. Close by, on the USC campus, the firm is rehousing the interdisciplinary Iovine Young Academy. A new production facility will enlarge the scope of the Center Theater Group downtown, and a state-of-the-art glass block will extend the Santa Monica City Hall.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In person Fisher is as quiet and thoughtful as his architecture, describing himself as "a pragmatic Midwesterner, the son of a hospital architect with a stack of books on Frank Lloyd Wright." His mother shared her love of art, taking him to drawing classes and the Cleveland Art Institute. After studying art at Oberlin, he drove to L.A. and secured his Master of Architecture degree at UCLA in 1978. Inspired by a Frank Gehry lecture on the Ron Davis studio in Malibu, he applied for a job and was told they had no work. "The next day, Gehry called back to say his marketing person had quit and he needed someone right away to fill in," Fisher recalls. "It was a great way to learn, and I graduated to model-making and design. He had a habit of giving young people responsibility, having them work from a little sketch."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1756,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/MoMAPS1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1756"/><figcaption>MoMA PS1 / Michael Moran</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>As he was leaving Gehry's office, he designed the Caplin house in Venice, "which was loaded with every idea I'd had in architecture school." His debut as an independent practice was a modest house-studio for ceramicist Elsa Rady, the first of a series of collaborations with artists. In the mid-1980s he won a competition to create MoMA P.S.1 in the New York borough of Queens, converting a public school into a versatile exhibition space. While Gehry claimed he had merely cleaned up a garage to create the Temporary Contemporary in downtown L.A., Fisher took a more aggressive approach in New York, stripping and tearing out walls to create rough, edgy spaces that would give artists total freedom. Gordon Matta-Clark had fun with a chain saw, and others have burrowed into the floor. Both galleries celebrate the excitement of creativity.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Adaptive re-use is a major part of the practice. A Santa Monica telephone company building was remodeled to house the Eli Broad collection, with beams and skylights replacing a forest of columns. A street-car depot was transformed into Bergamot Station, the most successful concentration of galleries in L.A. A Spanish-revival PacBell service facility in Harvard Heights became the Jane B. Eisner Middle School. The firm also turned a vintage guest house into the Annenberg Community Beach House in Santa Monica and gave new life to Sunnylands, the Annenbergs' estate in Rancho Mirage.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>"I'm not seen as an architect who produces signature work," Fisher admits. "Buildings should respond to their setting, so each one is different. That's a problem when people come to our office expecting to find a design they can select—'I'll have one of those'—and we tell them we don't yet know what it should look like."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The advantage of this approach is that Fisher's buildings don't go out of fashion or outlive their usefulness. Private art galleries are often ephemeral, but L.A. Louver in Venice looks as fresh as when it was completed in 1994. A crisp cubist composition of stucco, steel and concrete block is carved away to provide a gated entry court and an enclosed terrace that evokes a James Turrell Sky Space. As in P.S.1, a diversity of spaces are available for the installation of artworks, and it's a good place to catch up on the latest work of David Hockney.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1757,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/LALouver.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1757"/><figcaption>LA Louver / Tim Street-Porter</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>When the Huntington mansion was restored a decade ago, the board realized that they could build a new gallery to house the popular artworks for almost the same cost as putting them in storage. Fisher's team rose to the challenge of extending the Virginia Steele Scott Galleries of American Art, grafting the Erburu contemporary wing onto a neoclassical building and creating a seamless joinery within. They took inspiration from the skylit Dulwich Art Gallery near London, a pace-setting design two centuries old, which also provided a model for Richard Meier's Getty Museum.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The new Huntington galleries open up to nature through steel-framed walls of glass, and the temporary installation of classic English paintings was a huge success. As collector Frances Brody observed, "I don't think they should put the pictures back in the house—they look better here." In 2016 Fisher inserted another suite of galleries to house the Fielding Collection of early-American art and artifacts. Most recently the firm has reconfigured LACMA's Resnick Gallery to accommodate a wide diversity of exhibitions in a pinwheel plan of semi-enclosed spaces. That saves the expense and waste of putting up and tearing down drywall partitions for each show.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Watercolors provide Fisher with an escape from the rigors of architectural design as well as a sketchpad for future projects. "They force me to slow down and lose control, because once you've applied brush to paper, you can't undo it. To me it's about looking, and every form of representation distills the essence of what we see."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1758,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/NaturalHistoryMuseum.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1758"/><figcaption>Natural History Museum West-South Project / FF&amp;P</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The hands-on approach that has served Fisher so well feeds into the larger, more public projects he is currently designing. "One of the glories of architecture is how big it is and how many things it touches," he observes. "We want to demystify the experience of going to the Natural History Museum, especially for first-timers. Our design is all about transparency and connectivity, breaking down barriers between the activities within and those of a park that will host the Olympics for the third time in 2028."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Text:&nbsp;Michael Webb // Portrait:&nbsp;Sam Frost</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Read the original DesignLA/LA Times article <a href="http://edition.pagesuite.com/html5/reader/production/default.aspx?pubname=&amp;edid=dd1f0084-b91f-4866-b8d9-e10dc61a66ab&amp;pnum=94">HERE</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2018-04-04 13:37:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1486</ID>
		<Title>Mariam Mojdehi - Living Future 18</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The city of Santa Monica is building the first Living Building Challenge in Southern California. It will also be one of the first municipally owned Living Building Challenge projects, and likely the most densely populated building to earn the Certification. These reasons create unique challenges for the design team, but also as provide an exciting opportunity to advocate for better design as a Public Good. Through this project, the design team has advocated for greener building codes, greater transparency in the public process, innovative precedents for design build projects, and a better understanding of how material selection impacts environmental justice.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This session will focus on a case study of the challenges and opportunities presented by a municipal Living Building Challenge project. The City of Santa Monica will introduce the project and its unique design features, as well discuss the impact that the public review process plays in creating a more transparent approach to the design and construction process.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Find out more about this speaker series and the "unconference" in Portland, Oregon <a href="http://2018.livingfutureunconference.org/event/redefining-the-public-good-the-city-of-santa-monica-and-the-living-building-challenge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">HERE</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2018-04-05 11:45:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1488</ID>
		<Title><![CDATA[The Getty Villa Reopens with a "Fresh Twist"]]></Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>[Image:&nbsp;Getty Villa / © J. Paul Getty Trust]</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The revamp, spearheaded by Timothy Potts, the director of the J. Paul Getty Museum, carves out an additional 3,000 sq. ft of exhibition space and brings works out of storage. The emphasis, Potts says, will be on the artistic qualities and stylistic evolution of the artefacts over time. But the Getty’s collection—housed since 1974 in this full-scale replica of the Villa dei Papiri at Herculaneum—is limited to Greek and Roman art, and “classical art did not come about in a bubble”, he says.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Read the full article on <a href="https://www.theartnewspaper.com/news/getty-villa-renovation" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Art Newspaper</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:separator -->
<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>
<!-- /wp:separator -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>LOS ANGELES – Art and architecture seamlessly stand the test of time at the re-envisioned Getty Villa in Malibu. Working with Getty Museum Director Timothy Potts, FF&amp;P created and redefined spaces that respect the civic realm and landscape of the Villa’s historic exhibits. FF&amp;P worked with Potts on the historic renovation of the originally-designed complex by Langdon Wilson Architects (1974) which was previously renovated by Machado and Silvetti Associates (2006).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The Villa underwent this most recent renovation in response to the desire to organize the collections in chronological “historic” order rather than thematic order. In doing so, approximately 3,000 square feet of underutilized space was uncovered for exhibition galleries, allowing the team to find new homes for the Villa’s art pieces. Furthermore, art pieces previously kept in storage were brought out to breathe new life into the Villa’s exhibition galleries. A major highlight of the reinstallation is a newly renovated gallery on the first floor dedicated to the age of Alexander the Great and the Hellenistic world (336-30 BC). The centerpiece of this installation is <em>The Victorious Youth </em>(“Getty Bronze”), which can now be better appreciated for the masterpiece it is in the context of other objects of the same period and style, including a marble <em>Head of Alexander the Great </em>and groups of gold jewelry and luxurious silver vessels.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In addition to the challenge of maintaining operations during the construction process, FF&amp;P coordinated the effort of upgrading the museum’s mechanical and lighting systems. Careful consideration and respect to the architecture helped to drive the redesign with little noticeable aesthetic intervention - a new mechanical system was carefully integrated into the east garden landscape. In the end, what was left of the museum was a seamless integration of technology, art, and architecture, which is perhaps the hallmark of FF&amp;P and Frederick Fisher who, most recently, was described by the Los Angeles Times as “something of an invisible man” who “creates buildings that are acclaimed by their users but have often gone unnoticed by the world at large.” At the Villa, substance most undoubtedly reigns over show; a neutral color palette of navy and grey is used as the backdrop, allowing the art pieces to stand front and center. The same may be said now for the art as it takes the spotlight over architecture, allowing to complete the tag-team effort with previous design teams whose renovation sought to connect the architecture of the sprawling hillside campus.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The villa’s new space for temporary exhibitions will also host future installments in the series but its first show brings the classical era into the present. Plato in LA: Contemporary Artists’ Visions will display contemporary works, including new commissions, that respond to the Greek philosopher’s concepts, by artists such as Joseph Kosuth, Mike Kelley, Paul McCarthy, Paul Chan and Jeff Koons.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2018-04-16 11:06:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1490</ID>
		<Title>Otis College of Art and Design Campus Expansion Wins 2018 Green GOOD DESIGN Award</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The European Centre for Architecture Art Design and Urban Studies and The Chicago Athenaeum: Museum of Architecture and Design are pleased to announce that our joint venture project, Otis College of Art and Design Campus Expansion (Los Angeles)&nbsp;with Ehrlich Yanai Rhee Chaney (EYRC) Architects, has won a 2018 Green GOOD DESIGN™ Award.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Architecture, landscape architecture, urban planning projects, product, packaging, and graphic designs from over 20 nations were awarded with Green GOOD DESIGN™ 2018, representing the world’s most important manufacturers and design firms and leading FORTUNE 500 corporations that are forging a new emphasis on a more sustainable design and environment worldwide. This is the 10th year our institutions have developed this very specialized edition of the original GOOD DESIGN program, which was founded in Chicago in 1950 by Eero Saarinen and Charles and Ray Eames.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"left","id":1749,"width":248,"height":245,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/GoodDesignLogo.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1749" width="248" height="245"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Green GOOD DESIGN™ identifies and emphasizes the world’s most important examples of sustainable design and to develop a public awareness program to the general public about which global companies are doing the best job in ecological and sustainable design for our world environments. The original GOOD DESIGN® founded in Chicago in 1950 program remains the oldest and most important Awards Program worldwide.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>For the 2018 Green GOOD DESIGN™,&nbsp;hundreds of submissions were received from around the world. Members of The European Centre’s International Advisory Committee—worldwide leaders in the design industry— served as the jury and selected over 100 new products, programs, people, environmental planning, and architecture as outstanding examples of Green Design from 20 nations.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2018-04-19 12:19:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1492</ID>
		<Title>Artist in Residence: Asli Tusavul</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>FF&amp;P projects have an inherent relationship to the Arts. Aside from having a diverse team of talented individuals, we have a genuine&nbsp; interest in the fine arts and are active painters, sketchers, photographers, illustrators and graphic artists.&nbsp;<strong><em>Artist in Residence</em></strong>&nbsp;is a series of posts that will spotlight FF&amp;P's team members outside of the work they do as architects, designers, office managers, and marketers/communicators.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:separator -->
<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>
<!-- /wp:separator -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Asli Tusavul joined FF&amp;P in 2015 and has been involved with several of the firm’s most recent high profile projects such as the Pershing Square Renew Design Competition and the Santa Monica City Services Building. The latter of which, when built, will be the most eco-friendly municipal building of its kind and will set a standard for building construction (public or private) moving forward. A graduate of SCI-Arc and a licensed architect in Turkey (Union of Chambers of Turkish Engineers and Architects), Asli was included in Interiors + Sources magazine’s Designers to Watch and has been featured in online architecture and design blogs Dezeen, Designboom, SuckerPunch Daily and Arkitera.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"left","id":1743,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/BetterasaColor.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1743"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Asli has a deep working appreciation for the fine arts and was recently invited to showcase her work Better as a Color at BoldPas: An Art Takeover in Old Town Pasadena, California. The large scale art installation was comprised of thousands of straws sewn together and strung in rows across a 50-foot pre-fabricated steel frame. It serves as both a commentary on the environmental consequences of plastic straws and how small individual elements form urban spaces. It aims to connect people through coloration and sound. Addressing the issue of vast consumption of straws, this proposal suggests how straws can perform Better as a Color, Better as a Surface, Better as a Corridor and how they might be better at enhancing urban space and experiences.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1744,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/BAC-1_800.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1744"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1745,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/DSC00693_800.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1745"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2018-04-25 11:51:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1494</ID>
		<Title>McIlroy Center for Science and Innovation Ribbon-Cutting</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Shady Side Academy is a top-tier independent college preparatory school in the Pittsburgh area. &nbsp;Founded in 1883, the Academy prides itself on achieving academic excellence and innovation within a nurturing community, encouraging students to develop a strong sense of individuality and independence through critical thinking, creativity, and hands-on learning connected to real-life local and global issues. &nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The Shady Side Academy Center of Science and Innovation is a two-story science instruction facility nestled within the pastoral hills of its senior school’s historic campus. The building is sited in such a way as to create a “gateway” formed by Rowe Hall and the new science building on the main entry road to campus. &nbsp;In keeping with the campus’s Colonial Revival architectural aesthetic, a brick and glass façade complements the building’s context while simultaneously reinforcing its identity as a place of innovation, with details such as a glass frit pattern reminiscent of lung cells and microscopic steel structure highlighting its function as center of scientific inquiry. &nbsp;The horseshoe-shaped form comprised of three conjoined bar elements helps break down the building’s comparatively bulky footprint on the Shady Side campus. &nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Building access comes from multiple directions, and circulation runs around the horseshoe’s inner U, framing a three-sided outdoor courtyard for informal classes, gatherings, performances, and socializing. &nbsp;In addition to accommodating combination classroom/lab spaces for physics, biology, chemistry, and independent project research—as well as ancillary support spaces such as lab prep rooms and faculty offices—the facility includes a multipurpose collaboration room/lounge for display, small group meetings or work/study. &nbsp;This glassed-in, double-height space creates a sense of vertical connectivity, as well as a visual connection from the building’s most prominent public façade through to the central courtyard. &nbsp;The building’s roof accommodates energy collection equipment, offering an opportunity to both further the Academy’s mission of environmental stewardship and serve as a teaching tool.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/qXBLaGFtsW8?time_continue=176&amp;wmode=opaque&amp;enablejsapi=1" width="854" height="480" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"><br /></iframe></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2018-05-18 10:53:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1496</ID>
		<Title>The New Intersection of Art, Technology, and Business</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>[Image:&nbsp;USC Photo / Gus Ruelas]</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Current Jimmy Iovine and Andre Young Academy for Arts, Technology and the Business of Innovation students are housed in a prototype “garage” on campus and have outgrown their physical limitations. In 2016, USC engaged FF&amp;P and brightspot strategy to conduct a programming and concept design study for IYA’s permanent home. Primary objectives included achieving a universally high degree of knowledge exchange, resource accessibility, and delivery of services. To address these objectives with the physical environment, our team led an intensive, collaborative visioning &nbsp;period with IYA’s leadership, faculty, and students that resulted in a proposed 40,000 sf facility with expanded, state-of-the-art instruction, design, and fabrication spaces, areas for partner programs with related academic departments, and on-site office/work space for faculty and staff.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The IYA program consists of connecting/collision spaces for casual encounters and collaboration; flexible Instruction facilities; maker-spaces ranging from traditional wood and metal shops to technology-rich printing, media, and electronics labs; small- and large-group collaboration and conference areas, specified zones for student teams to work on long-term projects; and working spaces for IYA’s administration, faculty, and staff. The program distribution maximizes internal and external visual connectivity and has the flexibility to accommodate the physical evolution in keeping with this ever-evolving academic program. &nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The Iovine and Young Academy will become USC's 20th degree-granting school, under the leadership of Eric Muhl as the school's inaugural dean. With its focus on creativity, critical thinking, and collaboration, the Iovine and Young Academy has attracted broad support from the industry and widespread media acclaim. Students have received national academic awards and won top competitive internships and prizes from leading U.S. companies.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1739,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/Jimmy_Iovine_and_Andre_Young_Hall-20180619-160419.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1739"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This historic groundbreaking is being captured via time-lapse with OxBlue. Stay updated on the construction progress <a href="https://app.oxblue.com/open/usc/iovineyounghall" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">HERE</a>.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2018-06-01 09:31:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1498</ID>
		<Title>Reconsidering the Restroom: Opportunities of the Single Stall Public Restroom</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Join FF&amp;P's own Jake Lazere at this year's AIA Conference on Architecture in New York City on Saturday, June 23 at 4:00pm as he provides socio/political/personal context for designing today's restrooms as well as explore projects that have utilized this strategy to make extraordinary spaces.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Location: Hilton Midtown, 1335 6th Avenue, New York, NY 10019<br>More information <a href="http://conferenceonarchitecture.com/schedule/?gclid=CjwKCAjw9qfZBRA5EiwAiq0AbbCOSbiWp_F5fKmv_GHofICkrMI6mpBHSECMzqcXiBgSc5vGWYDSNBoCczUQAvD_BwE#poster-361171" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">HERE</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>If you are not able to attend, learn about this important topic below and share it.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:separator -->
<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>
<!-- /wp:separator -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Reconsidering the Restroom: Opportunities of the Single Stall Public Restroom</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Author: Jake Lazere, Associate AIA, Frederick Fisher and Partners</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"left","id":1724,"width":294,"height":392,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/Tongva_Aerial_6.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1724" width="294" height="392"/><figcaption>Tongva Park in Santa Monica from above.</figcaption></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Meandering along the curving paths nestled into the hills of Santa Monica’s Tongva Park, designed by James Corner Field Operations with Frederick Fisher and Partners Architects, one encounters various garden ‘eddies’ within the landscape. &nbsp;While most offer moments of serenity and pause, one of these opens into a wide passage connecting one path to another under a landscaped hill. &nbsp;This is Tongva Park’s public restroom—an eighteen-foot-wide by forty-foot-long breezeway flanked by toilet partitions and a trough sink on each side. &nbsp;Though a partial-height, wooden screen divides the ‘comfort station’ into two areas, little beyond door signage and color divides this space.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1725,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/Tongva_Twilight17.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1725"/><figcaption>The restroom at Tongva Park</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The Tongva Park restroom is one of several single stall public restrooms that Frederick Fisher and Partners (FF&amp;P) has recently completed. &nbsp;Single stall restrooms are a group of individual toilet compartments available to all users, regardless of gender, with sinks either inside them or in common handwashing areas. Each of these projects explores the opportunities of single stall restrooms as an alternative to conventional sex-specific, multi-user restrooms.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2><strong>In keeping with the core values of FF&amp;P’s Southern California-based practice, the comfort station’s architecture makes little distinction between indoor and outdoor living.</strong></h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"right","id":1726,"width":270,"height":175,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/PGW-FFPComfortStationDiagramsPage004.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1726" width="270" height="175"/><figcaption>A section of Tongva Park's comfort station.</figcaption></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The openness of Tongva Park’s restroom was not intended to make a political statement; rather, it was an attempt to integrate the facility more fluidly into its surrounding landscape. &nbsp;In keeping with the core values of FF&amp;P’s Southern California-based practice, the restroom’s architecture makes little distinction between indoor and outdoor. &nbsp;Individual toilet compartments and communal sink areas are open to nature on three sides – including a large, square opening to the sky above. &nbsp;Natural light illuminates the restroom from multiple directions. The space’s porosity also takes advantage of its location one block from the Pacific Ocean, enabling the coastal breeze to provide continuous natural ventilation—an issue Project Manager John Berley notes as one of the biggest challenges in restroom design. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1727,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/extract_restroom.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1727"/><figcaption>A single stall restroom is an aggregation of individual toilet compartments available to all users. The sinks are either located in the toilet compartments themselves or in a common space. Traditional restrooms are two sex-specific, multi-user enclosed rooms.</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The restroom’s open plan also addresses another important issue for the City of Santa Monica: security. &nbsp;Karen Ginsberg, Director of Community and Cultural Services, explains that given Santa Monica’s large homeless population, people have recently come to feel that enclosed public restrooms invite loitering and other illegal activities, but “public restrooms with individual stalls and common sinks provide privacy for patrons.” &nbsp;The stalls offer more privacy than a typical toilet partition; they have solid walls, are eight feet tall, and have minimal gaps at the base of the door. Outside of the private toilet stalls, the visibility of the common sinks to the rest of the park prevents illicit activities from occuring.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1728,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/IMG_9699.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1728"/><figcaption>The porosity of Tongva Park's Comfort Station contributes to its daylighting, ventilation, and perceived safety.</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>In keeping with the core values of FF&amp;P’s Southern California-based practice, the comfort station’s architecture makes little distinction between indoor and outdoor living.&nbsp; - Karen Ginsberg</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"right","id":1729,"width":280,"height":643,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/extract_restroom_2.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1729" width="280" height="643"/><figcaption>Three design iterations depict the restrooms' transformation from traditional sex-specific, multi-user restrooms with their own respective entrances (A) to the built design's single stall restroom with a common sink area (C).</figcaption></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>According to Ginsberg, when the city of Santa Monica first began implementing more open designs for its public restrooms approximately fifteen years ago, the idea of single stall restrooms replacing sex-specific, multi-user toilet rooms initially faced opposition, particularly from mothers with young children who were concerned for their children’s safety. &nbsp;Since then, however, general opinion in the progressive city has shifted. &nbsp;Current restroom projects like Clover Park are designed as single stall restrooms, a decision that both demonstrates the shift in local public opinion and follows the lead of the State of California, which implemented Assembly Bill 1732 on March 1, 2017, requiring all single-occupancy public restrooms statewide to be all-gender.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Assembly Bill 1732 was authored by Assemblyman Phil Ting of San Francisco, who commented that with the bill’s passage, “California is charting a new course for equality. Restricting access to single-user restrooms by gender defies common sense and disproportionately burdens the LGBT community, women, and parents or caretakers of dependents of the opposite gender.” The City of Santa Monica has worked with Scott Turner Schofield, consultant and educator on transgender issues, on ensuring equal access at several of their existing facilities. The Manager of Santa Monica’s Annenberg Community Beach House, Nan Friedman, explains that “he is looking into the the current ‘policy, customer service, and signage’ for the existing facilities to get ahead of any issues, to be as prepared as we can from a customer service standpoint, as well as to consider any architectural changes.”</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"left","id":1730,"width":285,"height":214,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/FullSizeRender.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1730" width="285" height="214"/><figcaption>The showers at the Annenberg Beach House are open to the changing area.</figcaption></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The design of the Beach House by Frederick Fisher and Partners was initiated in 2005, before the office began exploring the benefits of the single stall restroom or looking into opportunities for making changing rooms more private for their individual users. The Beach House currently offers two restroom areas servicing the outdoor recreational spaces – one servicing the beach, playground, and café, and the other with changing rooms by the pool. Both spaces are open air and accessed from outside. Both spaces are sex-specific, multi-user rooms. Project Manager John Berley notes that at the time, “we treated the changing rooms like typical lockers rooms” – rooms with open showers connected to open changing areas. Not only has the lack of privacy in the changing rooms deterred individuals from using the public showers, the gender-designations of each room have become a customer service challenge. There have mostly been complaints about the children of opposite sex parents in changing rooms.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1731,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/415-PLANChangingRooms.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1731"/><figcaption>Plan of the sex-specific changing rooms at the Annenberg Community Beach House. The family changing room currently does not include a shower.</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Scott Turner Schofield hopes to work with the city Santa Monica to “create a culture within each space where everyone is respectful of all its users.” His experience working with institutions on diversity education began in college when he transitioned from woman to man. At the time, his alma mater, Emory University, had no policies in place on how to accommodate and support Schofield’s transition and its implications on his day-to-day life on campus. His work has since contributed to policies at numerous universities and businesses. For Santa Monica’s public facilities, he is currently working on creating a policy around appropriate behavior in changing rooms, training the facility’s staff on how to implement the policy, and helping them to expand their family bathroom to include a shower for those seeking a private changing experience. Scott notes that unless the architecture is different, his work will primarily revolve around signage, policy, and training on appropriate customer service, so that occupants “can inhabit the provided spaces and not have to think too much about it.”</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1732,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/GettyRestroom-SansGetty-Salmon.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1732"/><figcaption>The restroom acts as one stop along an architectural promenade.</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>"[The goal is] to create a culture within each space where everyone is respectful of all its users."&nbsp; - Scott Turner Schofield</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Schofield previously worked with a large theater with two small, sex-specific restrooms that were overwhelmed by crowds at intermission. He suggested to remove the gender designation from the restrooms to enable a quicker flow for its users. One line for 6 plumbing fixtures moves faster than two lines for only 2-4 plumbing fixtures. The result was a change in signage. Since the men’s room had urinals, the signs on each room indicate which plumbing fixtures are inside with a new sign in between reading “all bodies welcome”. Those who do not want to use the room with urinals do not have to, but everyone is welcome to use any fixture.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"left","id":1733,"width":318,"height":522,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/415-PLAN.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1733" width="318" height="522"/><figcaption>(top) before; (bottom) after. A minor renovation to the Annenberg Community Beach House's public restrooms would convert them from sex-specific restrooms to single stall restrooms.</figcaption></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Despite this clever semiotic shift, Schofield’s anecdote confirms FF&amp;P’s current intent to consider such circumstances during the initial phases of a spaces’ design. We at Frederick Fisher and Partners hope the Beach House will be able to amend its current restrooms that services the cafe, playground, and beach by removing the exterior partition between the men’s and women’s restrooms, converting the facility into single stalls. This would accommodate the large number beach-time users by offering two way of entering and exiting the restroom, more fixtures per individual, and more wheelchair accessible stalls for each user who requires one.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>As opposed to sex-specific restroom rooms, single-stall restrooms present the opportunity to design more porous spaces, which helps improve circulation. Frederick Fisher and Partners has explored how single stall restrooms can improve the ‘flow’ of groups at educational and cultural institutions. Path of travel for a public restroom has individual toilet compartments on either side with a common sink area between. For the school tours that use this restroom, boys and girls form a single queue, enter the structure, use the first available toilet stall, rejoin his or her classmates at the central sinks to wash their hands together, and then proceed beyond to join a teacher or chaperone for the rest of the tour. FF&amp;P’s work with cultural and educational institutions has taught us that sex-specific, multi-user restrooms become essentially dead-end corridors that do not support queuing. Moreover, monitoring student behavior in these rooms becomes challenging because often teachers and chaperones are women, and no one is monitoring student behavior in the men’s restroom.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>One concern clients have expressed about single stall restrooms is whether they increase the size of the restroom area. These restrooms often replace what was a urinal with a toilet compartment. The International Plumbing Code, however, requires the same amount of space between urinals (thirty inches) as the width of a minimum toilet compartment. And while less space is required in front of the urinal, they most often take up the same amount of space as a toilet compartment when laid out in a men’s restroom. A comparison of two FF&amp;P restroom projects - a single stall restroom and a traditional restroom - shows that this single stall restroom is actually a smaller footprint than the sex-specific, multi-user restroom.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In addition to increasing efficiency, single stall public restrooms provide the opportunity to create spaces that communalize private rituals and bring people together. In general, we think fewer internal separations and boundaries make better environments in all types of spaces. Frederick Fisher notes the value of moving the more communal elements of restrooms like hand-washing “out of the deep, dark, cloistered corners into light, open spaces where serendipitous encounters can occur.” &nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Fisher’s embrace of spatial and inter-personal connectivity, even in sites of what are conventionally private rituals, can be traced to his involvement in the 1970s with the art publication Wet: the Magazine of Gourmet Bathing, founded by Leonard Koren. &nbsp;Trained as an architect, Koren wrote that the “the closest correlative” to communalizing the act of bathing “could be the tea ceremonies of the Taoist and Buddhists, in which elaborate rituals have evolved around a daily act as commonplace in Eastern cultures as bathing and shoe-tying.” Observing Koren’s celebration of friends gathering in a spa to enjoy each other’s company and the sensory pleasure of immersion in water—a commonplace activity in other cultures—Fisher came to appreciate his attempts to “demystify and destigmatize bathing,” removing the ritual’s shameful connotations through humor and delight. &nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1734,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/WET-cover-issue3_525.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1734"/><figcaption>An early cover of Wet Magazine, depicting Leonard Koren's photography celebrating bathing.</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>"...the tea ceremonies of the Taoist and Buddhists, in which elaborate rituals have evolved around a daily act as commonplace in Eastern cultures as bathing and shoe-tying.&nbsp; - Leonard Koren</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The public restrooms Frederick Fisher and Partners designs are certainly not trying to de-privatize what happens behind the toilet partition; rather, to reconsider the notion of the public restroom as a ‘cloistered’ private room that isolates people. This means respecting individuals’ needs for privacy with individual toilet compartments, while simultaneously communalizing those rituals that can help bring people together like hand washing in a common space.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"left","id":1735,"width":312,"height":177,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/Crossroads_12-760x430-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1735" width="312" height="177"/><figcaption>An outdoor teaching facility along an exterior corridor at Crossroads School for the Arts and Sciences.</figcaption></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>FF&amp;P completed a restroom facility in 2015 with common sinks for a new science education building at Crossroads School for Arts &amp; Sciences in Santa Monica. &nbsp;Given the area’s mild climate, circulation within the science building occurs outside. &nbsp;The building’s wide exterior corridors are programmed as collaborative spaces, such as outdoor teaching facilities and flexible gathering spaces.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1682,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/CrossroadsBathroom.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1682"/><figcaption>The hand washing station at the restroom at Crossroads School of Arts and Sciences</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"left","id":1736,"width":266,"height":320,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/CSB-A2-02.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1736" width="266" height="320"/><figcaption>Plan of the restrooms in Crossroads School of Arts and Sciences' new science building</figcaption></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Located on the second floor, the building’s main restroom operates in part as just another open, exterior space. &nbsp;To access the toilet compartments, students first pass through a communal hand washing area that is minimally separated from the adjacent walkway.&nbsp; Past the hand washing area are two rows of full-height, private, all-gender toilet compartments.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A progressive school with an active LGBTQ student organization called the “Pride Club,” Crossroads has in fact decided as an institution to remove gender designations from all its restroom facilities. &nbsp;Crossroads student Eli Offer has observed that the lack of gender designation was “originally a little weird and people thought one side would become gendered, but that wasn’t the case.” Now, he says, “after class everyone visits the restroom together. &nbsp;It’s something you do with your friends—you don’t have to separate.” &nbsp;Regarding the restroom in the new science building, Head of School Bob Riddle confirms that not only did the school not “face any institutional challenges to installing all-gender restrooms in the Science Education &amp; Research Facility, but the only opinions [we’ve] heard have been positive.”</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>"After class everyone visits the restroom together. &nbsp;It’s something you do with your friends—you don’t have to separate."&nbsp; - Eli Offer</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>These restroom projects by FF&amp;P detail creative uses of space that are made possible by designing single-stall restrooms instead of sex-specific, multi-user restrooms. They provide opportunities to connect people with their exterior environments, improve efficiency and flow, increase safety, and communalize social rituals. These restrooms offer flexibility - both in terms of spatial design and also for different users. With them, parents with children of the opposite sex, caretakers of the elderly of the opposite sex as well as transgender and gender non-conforming individuals do not need to think about which is the appropriate room for them and their families.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1720,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/ACBH_0W6D7754_RGBcopy.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1720"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Theorist Judith Butler advocates “not to celebrate difference as such, but to establish more inclusive conditions for sheltering and maintaining life that resists models of assimilation.” FF&amp;P explores this idea through its designs. &nbsp;Fisher himself often references the concept of ‘loose fit, long life.’ &nbsp;In other words, architecture that is flexible and allows for change—whether in terms of function, character, or plumbing—has a better chance of withstanding the test of time. &nbsp;Focusing on the individual user and not specifying specific user groups, single stall restrooms provide a loose fit for our diverse and rapidly evolving culture and therefore have a better chance of having a long lifespan.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>"not to celebrate difference as such but to establish more inclusive conditions for sheltering and maintaining life that resists models of assimilation"&nbsp; - Judith Butler</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>We at Frederick Fisher and Partners believe that no space should ever cause people to feel anxiety or exclusion; rather, good design should bring people together, give them access to light and air, and embrace the functions of everyday life. &nbsp;Ultimately, we believe that life should be improved through architecture – even in the restroom.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2018-06-18 12:05:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1500</ID>
		<Title>Joe Coriaty Accepted into AIA College of Fellows</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The 2018 Jury of Fellows from the American Institute of Architects (AIA) elevated 152 member-architects to its prestigious College of Fellows, an honor awarded to members who have made significant contributions to the architecture profession. The fellows were honored at a ceremony on June 22 at the AIA Conference on Architecture in NYC.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Congratulations, Joe!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:separator -->
<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>
<!-- /wp:separator -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Author: Larisa Forester, CPSM, Associate AIA, Frederick Fisher and Partners</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Joe firmly believes his designs positively impact the lives of its users by encouraging users to interact, create, hack, and disrupt the mundane to discover new ideas and better their surrounding communities.</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>For Joe, the city has always been an exhilarating place. Energy, people, shops, offices, factories - they all combine to create an interactive synergy unique to an urban environment. This is the atmosphere Joe infuses in his design. He embodies Ray Oldenburg’s “Third Place” in the makerspaces of civic, academic and cultural realms, making them naturally spaces where people gather. Socially vibrant, Joe’s designs foster the open exchange between public and private areas, indoor and outdoor, and community.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Joe attended the University of Detroit for architecture in 1974 at a time when there were few architecture jobs, so during the summers he worked at his father’s factory. One year he ran blue prints. The next he detailed parts for industrial machinery. Another year he ran the machines that produced the Bricklin rubber bumpers. When vinyl-covered foam became standard for car seats, Joe worked with the R&amp;D team to conceptualize, design, and create the new machines.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>“This crazy ingenuity that exists in Detroit using a group of diverse individuals to figure out a process that creates something new to get extraordinary results is what I strive to recreate with visionary placemaking and innovative makerspaces. Buildings themselves are simply a collection of wood, steel, brick, and glass, but great buildings become an anchor in the community and create their own harmony of culture, interaction, and memories.”</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1719,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/CrossroadsElevation_02.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1719"/><figcaption>Crossroads School of Arts and Sciences</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Joe is known for spreading his love and passion of getting “hands-on” with architectural design. From bringing Crossroads School for the Arts and Sciences students into work sessions to help design and construct their school science pavilion to inventing a built stack cast concrete factory atop the shifting ocean sands of the Annenberg Community Beach House site to working directly with an overseas building skin manufacturer to cut production cost by 50% at Caltech’s Annenberg Center for Information Science and Technology, Joe’s influence on creative space design and the individuals who use them continues to influence and shape the architectural world. He sees the big picture of the importance of minute differences in user interactions within his spaces and how those associations impact their future success.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1720,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/ACBH_0W6D7754_RGBcopy.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1720"/><figcaption>Annenberg Community Beach House</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Even while participating in international design competitions, volunteering in post-disaster reconstruction, leading projects on some of the world’s most prestigious ivy league campuses and serving on various design juries, Joe has always found time to be a mentor. He guided young architects through the intricacies of collaborative design for cultural institutions in Berlin and Japan and as a first responder after their devastating earthquake, he developed the system for Haitian engineers to reconstruct their school structures quickly, safely, and efficiently. He is leading revolutionary facility design with the University of Southern California’s new Jimmy Iovine and Andre Young Academy of Arts, Technology, and the Business of Innovation, the renovation of Princeton University’s historic Firestone Library, and the construction of the world’s first Living &nbsp;Building Challenge civic building. He also sits on juries and lectures at the University of Southern California, UCLA, Woodbury University, and the University of Detroit.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Joe doesn’t let his busy schedule prevent him from connecting with the younger generations, no matter if they are poised to be future designers, entrepreneurs, or food critics. He has helped now-colleagues discover their love of architecture over law school, political science, even over a promising golf career.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>“It’s one of the best feelings to know I made a difference in someone’s life just by sharing something I love with them.”</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1721,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/image-asset-2.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1721"/><figcaption>Joe receiving his medal at the AIA College of Fellows Investiture Ceremony at St. Patrick's Cathedral in New York City on June 22, 2018 | Photo: Matthew Kelley (FF&amp;P New York)</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2018-06-26 13:35:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1502</ID>
		<Title><![CDATA[Reinventing FF&amp;P]]></Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>As Frederick Fisher and Partners embarks on a new decade of practice, we wanted to evolve our brand by way of a new visual identity and website experience. And just as we get excited and inspired to start a new project, we were ready to start doing what we often do best: <em>reinvent.</em></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1708,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/FFPOld.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1708"/><figcaption>Before the rebrand</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Over the course of the last 35 years we’ve had the privilege of collaborating with a number of institutions, individuals, and businesses. With each, we’ve learned that in order to do anything of merit, it can’t be done alone. Nor can it be done in a one-sided manner. There must be true collaboration to achieve something genuine. Something truly impactful. Something “timeless.”</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>One of the many privileges we’ve had was getting to partner with the team at <a href="http://commonwealth-projects.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Commonwealth Projects</a>. Their heart for the work they get to do is extremely sincere, and that is felt in what they design.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>“FF&amp;P’s care, commitment and open mind throughout the rebranding process was crucial to the success of the project and a testament to the quality of their practice. The new identity is a true reflection of the firm’s ethos and designed to facilitate their pragmatic and dynamic work.”&nbsp; – Daniel Desure, Founder, Commonwealth Projects</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In the end, a new visual identity and online experience was created that not only showcases our work but also communicates the values within the work we do. And because our team achieved a balance between aesthetics and pragmatics, the result was an identity with lasting value.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1709,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/FFP_Brand_Edit1-1-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1709"/><figcaption>Rebranded marketing collateral.</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>We realized that a successful campaign required more than a revamped logo. It demanded a new firm goal, message, a vision that inspires others to see us in a new light.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>We sought to set ourselves apart from our competitors. We are sensitive to improving lives through architecture by first and foremost always knowing who our clients are. We don’t create and design after a handshake. We build a relationship and learn more about how we can fit into their world and then hit the ground running.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"center","id":1710,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/FFP_Logo_Primary_Stacked.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1710"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Our new logo is bold but adaptable to different aesthetics and applications. It is functional as it is an extension of our practice.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"center","id":1711,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/FFP_Logo_Abbrev_Horiz.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1711"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In addition to our new primary logo, we wanted to create a versatile and abbreviated version to use for our marketing efforts. It also serves another purpose. While our President and founder is still wholeheartedly engaged in the design process, we know that the future of our firm relies on the strength of its successors. The abbreviated FF&amp;P logo communicates and symbolizes a path towards shaping the future of the firm.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Frederick Fisher and Partners has a simple mission:</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":1} -->
<h1><strong>Improve lives through architecture.</strong></h1>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In creating a new visual aesthetic for our firm, we wanted to be forward-thinking – FF&amp;P is continuously adapting and providing new ways to approach projects and meet our client’s demands. At FF&amp;P, our mission is to improve lives through architecture. It’s a simple statement that speaks to what is inherent in the DNA of our firm culture. Each one of us comes to work every day to make an impact, no matter how big or how small it may be.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1712,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/FFPNewColor.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1712"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Color played an important consideration in our rebrand identity system. In general, colors have a significant impact on people’s emotional state. They have a wide variety of specific mental associations. In fact, the effects are physiological, psychological and sociological.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Color selection is always the fun part for any brand ideation, and in our case, the colors were quite literally right under our noses - under our founder's nose, to be exact, as it caught Commonweath Project's eye as he began to sketch. That's how our coral accent color landed in our rebrand. It complements our style with just the right amount of punctuation. The dark, bold blue color in our swatch is a calming primary color we were drawn to. And the combination of both, when used in tandem, provides a distinct look that helps to define our brand.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1713,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/Web_Home2.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1713"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Important to our rebrand was a complete website redesign. The updated site includes changes to navigation, with dropdown menus for both mobile and desktop versions. We’ve also improved the structure of our content. We wanted our content to be informative, to tell a story the way we would tell it. And we wanted to do it all in editorial fashion. When you land on our page, we want you to move throughout and experience the site. We want our audience to be able to navigate to exchanges of information without having to strain their eyes or dig through menus.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1714,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/Web_Delight2.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1714"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>There’s a whole host of smaller but impactful changes too, all to make your experience of the website that much better. ‘Delight’ becomes the home for what inspires us. We are influenced by architecture, art, performance, literature and everyday life. It is FF&amp;P’s hope that our audience is influenced by this, too, all in the effort to improve their own lives.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1715,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/Web_Home3.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1715"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>We have also created a host of new graphics, published a gallery’s worth of images, and included a few updates that have made the site easier to use. We invite you to experience them.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2018-07-12 13:05:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1504</ID>
		<Title>Summer Road Tripping</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>National Lampoon's Vacation, Pee-Wee's Big Adventure, Sideways, Y Tu Mama Tambien, The Motorcycle Diaries,&nbsp;The Blues Brothers - undeniably all titles of movies that celebrate the act of road tripping. It's a tradition for most families, a requirement for those who respect his/her solitude, and the best excuse to just hit the road with no destination in mind.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>We hope you're able to hit the road this hot summer. And if you are looking for some inspiration or have no clue on how to even begin planning your road trip, perhaps one of our Associates and KCRW DnA contributor, Marisa Kurtzman, will be able to point you in the right direction or embolden you to create your own journey.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In this <a href="https://kcrw.co/2aiZnLb" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">episode</a> of KCRW's Design and Architecture (DnA), Marisa sits down with Frances Anderton to recollect on a road trip she took last year and reflect on the lessons learned as an architect.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Read &amp; Listen <a href="https://www.kcrw.com/news-culture/shows/design-and-architecture/tunnels-planes-and-art-and-architecture-in-the-desert#seg-road-trip-to-pst-la-la" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">HERE</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2018-07-26 12:32:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1506</ID>
		<Title><![CDATA[What is an FF&amp;P internship?]]></Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The familiar sights and sounds of summer: waves crashing on the shore, birds chirping at the crack of dawn, toddlers giggling and skipping through the playground, swaying rocking chairs on porches, ice cold lemonade being stirred...and interns typing away at the keyboard or hastily running large format prints up and down the stairs?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Internships or co-ops provide a first-hand work experience, and enhance a student's academic/career/personal development. One of the recurring themes in any entry level job search is lack of experience - "Where do I get experience if no one is willing to hire me?" The answer lies in internships.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>An internship at Frederick Fisher and Partners offers you the chance to learn by doing in a setting where you are supervised by a work-place professional and have the opportunity to achieve your own learning goals, without the responsibilities of being a permanent employee. At FF&amp;P, we offer the opportunity for students to work with a team - people who aren’t just architects and designers, but mentors.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1694,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/Internships2018.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1694"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>We asked our summer interns:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>"What does an FF&amp;P internship mean to you?"&nbsp;</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"right","id":1695,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/Ada.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1695"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Ada Luchao Wang</strong> <em>(student, UCLA, Architecture &amp; Urban Design)</em>&nbsp; "The exciting part about working at FF&amp;P is that everyone here cares about design. It is very nice to see all this creative work happening with deep thinking. And people here are not afraid to try different design methods and use different materials. Also, the team knows each other pretty well - they even hang out a lot after work. My favorite part is we have all kinds of activities happening every week, including an ice-cream challenge, Wellness Wednesdays, sport outings, construction site visits, talks and all the museum outings. I really love all these events and appreciate people who are organizing it. I learned a lot and will take my experience here as inspiration."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"left","id":1696,"width":261,"height":196,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/tn.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1696" width="261" height="196"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Tom Niu</strong>&nbsp;<em>(student, UCLA, Architecture &amp; Urban Design)</em>&nbsp; "An internship at FF&amp;P for me means to explore what my interests are in the professional world as I approach my last year of architecture education. It means very much to me building friendships and gaining mentors outside the sphere of graduate students and instructors. Most importantly, it is the experience of working in an intimate and closely knitted firm that makes me cherish this experience even more."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"right","id":1697,"width":286,"height":215,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/ka.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1697" width="286" height="215"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Kathryn Ahmanson</strong> <em>(student, Claremont McKenna College, Art History and Art)</em>&nbsp; "My internship at FF&amp;P gives me the opportunity to learn about aspects of architecture that are not often discussed in school. While sitting in meetings I learn new terms and vocabulary, and working in the marketing department gives me some insight into the business side of architecture. This internship gives me a well-rounded perspective of the field, and I’m excited to continue to learn beyond the classroom."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"left","id":1698,"width":306,"height":394,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/Eric.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1698" width="306" height="394"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Eric Lin</strong> <em>(student, UCLA, Architecture &amp; Urban Design)</em>&nbsp; "The internship helps me gain efficiency in skills beyond what academia can provide, such as contract administration (CA) services. Moreover, my particular role with the Santa Monica City Services Building project allows me to be involved in the Living Building Challenge, one of the most progressive sustainable standards in architecture, and to be able to push it further by setting up a firm-wide material resource system."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:separator -->
<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>
<!-- /wp:separator -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Thank you to each of our interns this season!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>If you are interested in an internship with FF&amp;P, send an email and connect with us:&nbsp;<a href="mailto:info@fisherpartners.net">info@fisherpartners.ne</a>t. We look forward to hearing from you!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Who we want to work with </strong>- Each member of our talented studio brings a unique perspective, know-how, creativity, a love of learning, dedication, and enthusiasm to work every single day. We are looking for the best and the brightest - but not in the conventional sense. Although a passion for design and the architectural profession is a must, we seek team members and interns who are also innovative and full of new ideas, who aren't afraid to go out on a limb and try new things, who are adaptable and flexible, who take initiative and who will be our future leaders. Our firm culture is vibrant and enriched by projects we create. We collaborate with our clients and within our teams and encourage everyone to share their knowledge and ideas.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2018-08-10 09:46:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1508</ID>
		<Title>Progress</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Author: Summer Stuckey, Frederick Fisher and Partners</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Architecture enriches our lives emotionally, psychologically, and adds quality to our communities. It breaks down barriers and provides people a place to feel safe, build memories, and grow. FF&amp;P is enthusiastic and hopeful to see organizations like <a href="http://socalnoma.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Southern California Chapter for The National Organization of Minority Architects</a> seek progress towards education and careers for minority architects who have been underrepresented.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1701,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/2-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1701"/><figcaption>Jake Lazere | photo by: Summer Stuckey</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Providing youth with a wide range of career paths in architecture and various related fields of study is crucial. SoCal NOMA offers an annual summer camp providing hands on experience and implements the affect architectural design has on our communities. The camp is taught primarily but not exclusively by a diverse demographic of architects, engineers, interior designers, and urban planners.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1702,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/5.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1702"/><figcaption>Sapeer Hillel | photo by: Summer Stuckey</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>FF&amp;P had the opportunity to volunteer with SoCal NOMA’s 2018 summer camp, <em>Rams Landing Neighborhood Renewal Project</em>. Day 2 focused on Site Planning &amp;&nbsp;Design, mentors gave feedback to campers'&nbsp;on their homeless housing solutions homework assignment. Followed by a field trip to the Rams Stadium, site planning,&nbsp;design, drawings, and reviewing the process of permit requirements.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1700,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/1-4-1024x605.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1700"/><figcaption>SoCal NOMA campers | photo by: Summer Stuckey</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Students were given a presentation on planning and programming and were then expected to develop bubble diagrams based on their building types. FF&amp;P mentors helped campers develop floor plans and elevations.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Additionally, SoCal NOMA provides internships and a <a href="https://jobs.noma.net/jobs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">job board</a> offering various levels of experience from internships to senior level positions. The goal is to expand the diversity within this industry and showcase the influence culture has on design.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2018-08-16 10:26:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1510</ID>
		<Title>Creating More than Silver</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:image {"id":1677,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/Crossroads_Community_01-Copy-1-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1677"/><figcaption>Crossroads is not just a great place to learn science, it’s a great place to learn how to be a leader</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The Crossroads School for Arts and Sciences originally set a goal to achieve LEED Silver for its science facility and kiva-hut inspired student pavilion, but 2018 brought an even more valuable revelation. The building achieved LEED Gold, along with the rest of the campus - a big step above what was thought possible for this urban campus in an arid environment.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1678,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/Crossroads-Curtainwall-683x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1678"/><figcaption>Photovoltaic Panels gather solar energy and use it to power the building</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Contributing to the achievement are on-site photovoltaic solar panels using advanced energy metering to power to the building and absorb the heat and noise from the adjacent freeway, an extensive storm-water retention and filtration system, recycled denim insulation, extensive LED SMART lighting design, ample natural light and a rooftop butterfly garden that is home to migrating Monarch butterflies.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1679,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/Crossroads_Labs_02.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1679"/><figcaption>Hands-on learning is an every day exploration of scientific knowledge and theory</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>As a firm believer that children learn better and understand on a deeper level when they see, smell, touch, and experience their lessons, practicing what you preach is important at the Crossroads School for Arts and Sciences.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1680,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/CrossroadsPavilion_02-683x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1680"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Intentionally designed to celebrate the beauty in science, and the science behind art, the building itself is a visual teaching tool and artistic showcase. The pavilion roof installation by environmental artist Ned Kahn provides a glimpse of unseen phenomena - showcasing hidden wind/gravity interplay.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1681,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/FFA_XRDS_0409_F2.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1681"/><figcaption>The moving pavilion sculpture can be seen in action from nearly anywhere in the butterfly garden plaza below</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Exposed concrete, open building systems, and visible sustainability initiatives transform the structure into a habitable physics project. Large storefront windows create “living artwork” of the interior classroom and the exterior “Alley,” an all-school central plaza and gender-neutral restrooms with ceramic tiles patterned with the human molecular structure reflect the school’s liberal viewpoints.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1682,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/CrossroadsBathroom.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1682"/><figcaption>At Crossroads, inclusivity is a way of life - molecular structure tile patterns lead the way to the all gender restrooms</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>For more information on Crossroads’ recent LEED Gold achievement, visit the <a href="https://www.centerforgreenschools.org/leed-schools-are-making-big-strides-2018" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Center for Green Schools’ website</a>.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>For more information about the Crossroads’ building and site, <a href="https://fisherpartners.net/projects/crossroads/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">visit the FF&amp;P website</a>.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2018-09-11 12:58:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1512</ID>
		<Title>POWERFUL</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:image {"id":1670,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/380powerfulwomen.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1670"/><figcaption>Photography by: Nico Marques</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>“Be tenacious yet humble; be realistic but passionate; have opinions, but listen; be measured yet driven.” </strong>-Jennifer Luce, FAIA Principal, LUCE et Studio</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Author: Summer Stuckey, Frederick Fisher and Partners&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>On September 20th, FF&amp;P’s entire female staff (and a few of our male colleagues) had the privilege of attending Powerful, an annual conference organized by the AIA|LA’s WiA (Women in Architecture) committee.&nbsp; During a full day of speakers and panels, discussion sessions, and educational training, we learned about game-changing architectural projects and research, shared stories of struggle and success, heard rousing calls to action, and enjoyed a special spirit of camaraderie.&nbsp; For the women of FF&amp;P, Jennifer Luce’s words seemed to sum up not just the conference’s message, but perhaps the way we like to think about architectural practice itself.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Below are some of the ideas that we found particularly powerful.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1671,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/image-asset.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1671"/><figcaption>Powerful Conference organized by AIA| LA’s WiA<br>Photography by: Summer Stuckey</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>&nbsp;On design:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>&nbsp;Storytelling is important- for conveying design intent, for sharing history and learning from it, for human connection. How does a building tell a story?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>&nbsp;During their “tech talk,” Noni Pittenger (Design Engineer, CW Keller) and Kerenza Harris (Director of Design Technology, Morphosis) raised interesting questions about using virtual reality, architecture’s hottest new design tool.&nbsp; As we begin to experiment with VR in our practice, we are intrigued by the idea of using VR not necessarily as a way to make decisions about and finishes, but rather, as a means of truly understanding the body’s relationship to a building’s scale and sense of place.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"left","id":1672,"width":284,"height":213,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/EDIT12.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1672" width="284" height="213"/><figcaption>Laura Friedman discussing Inequity and bias.<br>Photography by: Summer Stuckey</figcaption></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>&nbsp;On inequity and bias:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Laura Friedman (Assistant Speaker pro Tempore, California State Assembly and Assembly Member, District 43/Glendale) cited a study illustrating skewed perceptions of women’s presence and participation in professional collaborations.&nbsp; If a table of colleagues includes 30% women, men tend to describe that gender split as 50/50; if the table is half women, men will view that number as being <em>mostly</em> women.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1673,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/IMG_9275.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1673"/><figcaption>Photography by: Summer Stuckey</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Belinda Morris (Founder &amp; President, Peoplescape Consulting Group) and Candice Gottlieb-Clark (Founder, Dynamic Team Solutions) followed-up with an eye-opening interactive discussion of unconscious gender bias, as well as how to confront it.&nbsp; Not surprisingly, gender bias begins when we are very young.&nbsp; According to Reshma Saujani, founder of Girls Who Code, in primary school, boys are taught to be brave and take risks, while girls are encouraged to be perfect.&nbsp; As women grow up and enter the workplace, we experience gender bias in many forms—both overt and subtle—across all industries, from professional sports to architecture.&nbsp; While we at FF&amp;P are lucky to be part of a diverse, open-minded cohort, it is still important to remember that as human beings with different life experiences, we all exhibit bias.&nbsp; The first step to moving past it is raising awareness- within ourselves, and within others.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"right","id":1674,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/IMG_9266.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1674"/><figcaption>Anne Schopf, AIA discussing Quiet Activism.<br>Photography by Summer Stuckey</figcaption></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>On speaking up:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Anne Schopf, AIA (Design Partner, Mahlum Architects) combined bravery and vulnerability in her discussion of “quiet activism.” While she urged us to embrace a cause we feel passionate about, she also recommended so in a way that feels personal and authentic.&nbsp; Even small-scale actions will add up, make an impact, and move us in the right directions.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>On leadership and mentorship:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Laura Friedman made an eloquent argument for women sticking together throughout their careers.&nbsp; As we gain more responsibility and achieve higher positions of leadership, we should strive to raise up the women following in our footsteps- not just to our level, but perhaps even higher.&nbsp; Because in turn, they will raise you up too.&nbsp; Whether it’s through sharing knowledge within our project teams or our Partners guiding our Next Generation of firm leaders, we at FF&amp;P understand that strong mentorship should be taken seriously as a benefit to everyone.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>We look forward to attending Powerful again next year, and we encourage everyone in our industry (women <em>and</em> men) to do the same.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2018-10-08 15:50:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1514</ID>
		<Title>Reinventing the Collection</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:quote -->
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p class="" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">“We wanted to reinvent how the collection was presented. <br>We wanted to better tell the story.”</p><p class="" style="white-space: pre-wrap;">-Jeffrey Spier, Senior Curator of Antiquities J. Paul Getty Museum</p></blockquote>
<!-- /wp:quote -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>&nbsp;Author: Summer Stuckey, Frederick Fisher and Partners</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"right","id":1685,"width":300,"height":217,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/FF-preferredpsed.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1685" width="300" height="217"/><figcaption>Frederick Fisher, founder of Frederick Fisher and Partners and Lauren Friedman, Campus Architect, J.Paul Getty Trust.</figcaption></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>On September 26th&nbsp;Frederick Fisher and Lauren Friedman, Campus Architect, J. Paul Getty Trust presented at the 2018 International Association of Museum Facility Administrators (IAMFA) Annual Conference. The IAMFA is an International nonprofit organization devoted to meeting the professional needs of facility and security administrators at cultural institutions.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1686,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/GettyEvent-03.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1686"/><figcaption>[Image: Getty Villa / © J. Paul Getty Trust]</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The presentation provided a window into the process and challenges associated to the re-organization of the Getty Villa Collection and was structured through the following topics:&nbsp; Vision, Team, Operations, Scope, Challenges and Material Samples.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:gallery {"ids":[1689,1688,1687]} -->
<figure class="wp-block-gallery columns-3 is-cropped"><ul class="blocks-gallery-grid"><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/3.png" alt="" data-id="1689" data-full-url="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/3.png" data-link="https://fisherpartners.net/reinventing-the-collection/attachment/3/" class="wp-image-1689"/></figure></li><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/20170628_073601_resized.jpg" alt="" data-id="1688" data-link="https://fisherpartners.net/reinventing-the-collection/20170628_073601_resized/" class="wp-image-1688"/></figure></li><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/IMG_1697Marble.jpg" alt="" data-id="1687" class="wp-image-1687"/></figure></li></ul></figure>
<!-- /wp:gallery -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>&nbsp;</strong>The reconfiguration of galleries was driven by a curatorial decision to present the collection of antiquities chronologically rather than thematically. This direction promotes a better understanding of the pieces in a wider cultural context. Through an inclusive and collaborative process, the Getty team, architects, exhibition designers, engineers and the contractors were able to establish common goals.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:gallery {"ids":[1690,1691]} -->
<figure class="wp-block-gallery columns-2 is-cropped"><ul class="blocks-gallery-grid"><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/image-asset-1.jpg" alt="" data-id="1690" data-link="https://fisherpartners.net/reinventing-the-collection/image-asset-1/" class="wp-image-1690"/><figcaption class="blocks-gallery-item__caption">Before</figcaption></figure></li><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/2.png" alt="" data-id="1691" data-full-url="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/2.png" data-link="https://fisherpartners.net/reinventing-the-collection/2-2/" class="wp-image-1691"/><figcaption class="blocks-gallery-item__caption">After<br>Photography: Takashige Ikawa</figcaption></figure></li></ul></figure>
<!-- /wp:gallery -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Rapid responses and clear lines of communication were required to complete the project on schedule. All the while working around the museum’s events and keeping 50% of the galleries open during the renovation. The teams goal was to improve lighting, environmental control, visitor support, and increased exhibition space.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2018-10-18 17:07:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1516</ID>
		<Title>The California/Swiss Connection</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Jake Lazere and David Manzano, designers from FF&amp;P’s Los Angeles office, just returned from a trip to Germany and Switzerland with the Swiss furniture manufacturer Vitra. Funny enough – Vitra’s foray into the furniture business began with another California/Swiss connection when the Fehlbaum family began manufacturing the furniture designs of Los Angeles designers, Ray and Charles Eames, in the 1950s for a European market.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1652,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/20034960_imagefromvitraswebsite.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1652"/><figcaption>Ray and Charles Eames, image courtesy of Vitra</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Jake and David began the trip in Cologne, Germany for Orgatec ’18, a trade fair focusing on new visions for the workplace. They next traveled to Basel, Switzerland to learn more about the furniture manufacturer Vitra and its unique design culture.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Orgatec was made up of numerous convention center halls filled with booths dedicated to the planning, installation, and design of the office environment and its objects. While the FF&amp;P designers greatly enjoyed exploring the halls, they most enjoyed hearing from the product and space designers about their work.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:gallery {"ids":[1653,1654]} -->
<figure class="wp-block-gallery columns-2 is-cropped"><ul class="blocks-gallery-grid"><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/Orgatec2.2.jpg" alt="" data-id="1653" data-link="https://fisherpartners.net/the-california-swiss-connection/orgatec2-2/" class="wp-image-1653"/><figcaption class="blocks-gallery-item__caption">A workplace installation of movable ‘dancing walls’ at Orgatec ‘18</figcaption></figure></li><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/Orgatec3.jpg" alt="" data-id="1654" data-full-url="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/Orgatec3.jpg" data-link="https://fisherpartners.net/the-california-swiss-connection/orgatec3/" class="wp-image-1654"/><figcaption class="blocks-gallery-item__caption">Jake testing Sevil Peach’s idea for a cantilevered desk at a window</figcaption></figure></li></ul></figure>
<!-- /wp:gallery -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Vitra had a large presence at the show with an entire exhibition hall dedicated to displaying the company’s current thinking on the workplace. Jake and David listened to London based architect Sevil Peach discuss her installation in the Vitra hall. She spoke of democratizing the workplace, giving each employee access to the best spaces in the office. Peach also inspired the FF&amp;P team with the concept of ‘landscaping the interior environment of the open office’ - in terms of how she considers proportion and color to create varied and humane workplaces. &nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Designer Jay Osgerby made the guys laugh with his quick wit as he discussed a new seating system, Soft Work, that he developed with his partner Edward Barber of the eponymous Barber &amp; Osgerby. Modular and almost domestic - this product was designed to address the increasing informality of workspaces, while also considering what makes for a great place to work - power, surfaces for writing/typing, and ergonomics.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The last stop on the trip was the Vitra Campus - Gehry, Ando, Siza, Hadid, Herzog &amp; de Meuron, SANAA, oh my! Exploring the campus was an amazing opportunity to see the work of some of the most influential architects of the 20th and 21st century in one location, on an active furniture manufacturing campus no less! The FF&amp;P designers greatly respect and appreciate the furniture manufacturer’s dedication to design - in the objects it produces, as well as the buildings and spaces it builds, and the independent museum that operates on its campus. And to think - this all got started with the help of a couple of Californians…</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1655,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/Vitra.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1655"/><figcaption>The Vitra Campus with Herzog and de Meuron’s Vitrahaus in the distance and the shadow of Carsten H<em>ö</em>ller’s Vitra Slide Tower on the lower left</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2018-11-21 12:36:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1518</ID>
		<Title>Perspectives on Progressive Employment Policies</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Author: Summer Stuckey, Frederick Fisher and Partners</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Cultivating a forward-thinking work space and implementing policies that reflect the pulse of our team is crucial. &nbsp;FF&amp;P was pleased to host AWA+D’s (Association for Women in Architecture + Design) discussion on <em>P.E.P Talk</em>: Perspectives on Progressive Employment Policies. The panelist highlighted, both employer and employee pros to integrating such policies.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"right","id":1664,"width":254,"height":185,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/1.24.19.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1664" width="254" height="185"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The advocacy committee shared different perspectives including career breaks to pursue higher education, flexible hours, working remotely, and assisting women and men to better balance their personal and professional lives.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>How we define ourselves, how a practice operates, and the balance between professional and personal lives are substantial ingredients to a successful work environment. Growing and maintaining an authentic DNA requires us to ask questions and be open minded to change. All while continuing to service our clients and projects with the same standard of excellence FF&amp;P has always been known for.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2019-01-25 09:08:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1520</ID>
		<Title>Big Apple</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Author: Summer Stuckey, Frederick Fisher and Partners</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>FF&amp;P is kicking off 2019 with the official expansion of our presence in New York. The journey began in 2012 when Matt Kelley, Senior Designer at Frederick Fisher &amp; Partners ventured to the big apple for a new life adventure. Fast forward several years and FF&amp;P has finally settled into its perfect New York home - a charming light-drenched work-space filled with thoughtful, innovative designers. Their focus is to continue creating the spaces developed by our West-Coast roots that deliver a holistic, timeless, and sustainable experience. Help us welcome our East Coast team as they spread the FF&amp;P mission to improve life through architecture.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1660,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/IMG_02861.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1660"/><figcaption>FF&amp;P NY Office</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Christina Kwak, Project Architect- graduated from the University of Colorado Boulder with a Bachelor of Environmental Design and from Columbia University GSAPP with a Master of Architecture. She has over 15 years of experience and has always been intrigued by all things too large or too small for the eye to see. She spends her time outside of the office gutting her house, making ice cream, being a parent and aspiring to travel more.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>William Vincent, Sr. Project Manager- received a Bachelor of Business Administration from the University of Mississippi and a Master of Architecture from Tulane University. He brings 27 years of experience that includes designing sets for Givenchy print ads (Richard Avedon photography), rock concerts, television commercial sets for Estee Lauder and L'Oreal, a theater set design for the Merchant / Ivory film “Heights”, starring Glenn Close, and numerous sets and props for Lady Gaga. William was a frequent guest critic at Tulane University while assisting in design studios, and reviews design projects at Parsons School of Design, Pratt University, City College of New York, and New York Institute of Technology.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1661,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/Summer.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1661"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Christian Menna, Design Team Member-&nbsp;is a designer of space and imagery through the art of storytelling. A Southern California native and avid traveler, Christian graduated with a B.Arch from NewSchool of Architecture &amp; Design, where he received the school’s Highest Design Award. While growing up in Southern California he was exposed to an abundance of arts, culture and a wide range of mid-century to contemporary architecture. He is passionate about contributing to an organization that pushes for progressive expressions of architecture. His previous work experience range from 2 person firms to world renowned architecture firms. His time outside of work is spent with friends, trying a new recipe, yoga, meditating, traveling, painting or sketching.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2019-02-18 15:23:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1522</ID>
		<Title>Sensibility in L.A?</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Author: Summer Stuckey, Frederick Fisher and Partners</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://fisherpartners.net/">FF&amp;P</a>&nbsp;Founder,&nbsp;<a href="https://fisherpartners.net/studio/?i=partners#partners">Frederick Fisher</a>&nbsp;will be participating in Occidental College’s&nbsp;<a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/register?orderid=d6ff274d3a0411e9b3d312541e7bbb3e&amp;client_token=7118c10d8db349b9b484e1137b590171&amp;eid=55586655182">3RD L.A. (Re)Designing LA&nbsp;</a>- a series of public conversations about L.A. and its built environment. The collective event led by Christopher Hawthorne, Los Angeles’ first Chief Design Officer, will highlight innovative design with an in-depth discussion specifically addressing climate change, protecting against displacement, and the conservation of neighborhood culture and history and&nbsp;will address questions such as: "What does it mean to create spaces that preserve and enhance design?" "What does it mean to echo the true spirit of Los Angeles?”&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Architects, planners, preservationist, and critics world-wide crave authenticity. Los Angeles is a city imbued with culture, iconic buildings, and history. From concert halls to stadiums, hilltop houses to historic retail, this seminar influences architects, designers, city officials, and community leaders to create a more thoughtful, productive, and inclusive built environment. Register here:&nbsp;<a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/register?orderid=d6ff274d3a0411e9b3d312541e7bbb3e&amp;client_token=7118c10d8db349b9b484e1137b590171&amp;eid=55586655182">3RD L.A. (Re)Designing L.A</a>.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2019-02-26 16:24:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1524</ID>
		<Title>The Heart of Princeton</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Author: Summer Stuckey, Frederick Fisher and Partners</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Every campus has a heart. The place where students, faculty, and staff just seem to naturally congregate and constantly used for reasons designers could never have imagined at the onset of the project. Sometimes the true heart of a campus is the campus green, a local coffee shop, and occasionally the student union on Main Street. At Princeton University, it’s historic Firestone Library.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"right","id":1642,"width":251,"height":330,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/Firestone-Ext1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1642" width="251" height="330"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Constructed in 1948 just after World War II, Firestone Library is the last gothic structure on campus. This renovation is a turning point in campus history requiring a thoughtful sensibility in its redesign.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The University entrusted FF&amp;P and Shepley Bulfinch&nbsp;to retain&nbsp;the library’s&nbsp;“DNA" and expand upon it with our own expertise. The resulting loft style interior uses openness, transparency, lighting, color, and fabric to subliminally lead visitors through the space, make them feel welcome, and inspire a sense of comfort.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1643,"width":580,"height":294,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/glass.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1643" width="580" height="294"/><figcaption>Photography: Shepley Bulfinch</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>&nbsp;Within the library, the Ellen and Leonard Milberg Gallery showcasing a collection of rare books and manuscripts is open to visitors following five long years of renovations. The vision for the space was to create an inviting atmosphere that celebrates the cherished rare items within and deconstruct the opaque barriers to these highly sensitive items with a “glass box” inviting those on the outside in.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1644,"width":579,"height":434,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/02.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1644" width="579" height="434"/><figcaption>Photography: Shepley Bulfinch</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"right","id":1645,"width":273,"height":193,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/03.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1645" width="273" height="193"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>&nbsp;The color palette transitions from dark brown north-facing book cases to white south-facing book cases in a subtle geographic orientation. The North area has a discovery-hub with movable furniture for students to collaborate and use as study space. Islands of study areas are interrupted with couches and chairs to offer additional informal opportunities to explore and learn.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"left","id":1646,"width":237,"height":165,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/OpenAsset_20151217151622_Page_1_Image_0005.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1646" width="237" height="165"/><figcaption>Photography: Shepley Bulfinch</figcaption></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>&nbsp;The notion of domesticity and transparency are woven throughout the library's mid-century interiors with hints of modernism. Students and faculty spend tremendous amounts of time in the library for&nbsp;countless activities that will undoubtedly change over time.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"width":573,"height":587,"className":"sqs-block-image-figure image-block-outer-wrapper image-block-v2 design-layout-poster combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none image-position-left"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image is-resized sqs-block-image-figure image-block-outer-wrapper image-block-v2 design-layout-poster combination-animation-none individual-animation-none individual-text-animation-none image-position-left"><img src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5ab536b77c9327e5eed2d6fc/1555529112333-22N05TKXYL41863VV8J6/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kC1H10YwAe4sEDdlObmadHhZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWEtT5uBSRWt4vQZAgTJucoTqqXjS3CfNDSuuf31e0tVF7ru2068B0LZotrk4wQh3vYzSAtoGzEMAkygvcVvSwzZYaohZIH84tU17bYDBjkmU/01.jpg" alt=" - " width="573" height="587"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The flexibility of the final design nurtures&nbsp;this diverse usage and establishes the&nbsp;Library&nbsp;as a timeless place of continuous connection, inspiration, intimacy, and learning.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2019-03-08 12:17:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1526</ID>
		<Title><![CDATA[Who’s designing? Who’s inspiring?&nbsp;We are.]]></Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:image {"align":"right","id":1635,"width":254,"height":254,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/FFPC-1024x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1635" width="254" height="254"/><figcaption>Interior Design, POWERGRID LA</figcaption></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Author: Summer Stuckey, Frederick Fisher and Partners</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Become enamored by our cities iconic development and explore&nbsp;<em>Interior Design’s</em>&nbsp;newest platform&nbsp;<a href="https://www.interiordesign.net/powergrid-la/top50/"><em>POWERGRID LA</em></a>. The magazine that’s known as an “essential authority” for professionals throughout the design process kicks off 2019 by highlighting the top 50 architecture firms that are shaping LA. &nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Ranging from small to extra-large the featured firms have "completed 248 developments for a total of 40 million square feet, with an average project size of 954,000 square feet” and over 670 developments on-the-boards totaling 135 million square feet. According to the article, half of the firms said they’re looking at mixed-use projects, including office, retail, and public-space work and a third of that is multi-family residential. The overall data was analyzed by Interior Design.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>As the architecture industry continues to evolve FF&amp;P will practice design organically while maintaining the city's historical DNA. Scroll through the images below to see 3 out of 8 FF&amp;P projects that made the list.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:gallery {"ids":[1637,1638,1639]} -->
<figure class="wp-block-gallery columns-3 is-cropped"><ul class="blocks-gallery-grid"><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/SWCorner.jpg" alt="" data-id="1637" data-link="https://fisherpartners.net/whos-designing-whos-inspiring-we-are/swcorner/" class="wp-image-1637"/></figure></li><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/01-LOOKINGSOUTHEAST.jpg" alt="" data-id="1638" data-link="https://fisherpartners.net/whos-designing-whos-inspiring-we-are/01-lookingsoutheast/" class="wp-image-1638"/></figure></li><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/view2-017.jpg" alt="" data-id="1639" data-full-url="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/view2-017.jpg" data-link="https://fisherpartners.net/whos-designing-whos-inspiring-we-are/view2-017/" class="wp-image-1639"/></figure></li></ul></figure>
<!-- /wp:gallery -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2019-03-21 15:15:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1528</ID>
		<Title><![CDATA[What's INN at the Institute for the Liberal Arts?]]></Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Author: Summer Stuckey, Frederick Fisher and Partners</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Vassar College is in the planning and design stages of a new Inn and Institute for the Liberal Arts. The 48,000 sq ft project will include 50 guest rooms, a restaurant, and convening space. The site is located just outside of the campus walls in a picturesque park adjacent to the historic Alumnae House. The project vision creates a space for faculty, students, innovators, leaders, and communities to exchange ideas and foster thoughtful dialogue, but also a social space connecting to town.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>FF&amp;P’s concept design combines contextual sensitivity, functionality, and an authentic expression of Vassar’s philosophical ideals. Providing an indoor-outdoor connection by creating natural light, views of the campus, and landscape. Vassar will also maintain the park-like atmosphere surrounding the historic campus. The design of the building preserves the domestic scale of the surrounding neighborhood by breaking the program into discrete elements; a three-story gable roof Inn, a two-story Institute with a restaurant below, and a glass lobby to create notion of a public living room.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1632,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/Capturefinal.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1632"/><figcaption>Aerial rendering of the Institute for the Liberal Arts and Inn</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The landscape design creates a welcoming approach with fully accessible pathways and highlights native plant species and on-site water filtration. Vassar holds a deep commitment to sustainability and green building practices which is foregrounded in the building’s high energy efficiency, well day-lit spaces, and the use of natural materials.&nbsp;FF&amp;P is hopeful to break ground in July of 2020 and aiming for the project to be completed by July 2022.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2019-04-12 11:32:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1530</ID>
		<Title>Desert X</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:image {"align":"right","id":1626,"width":229,"height":229,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/BUS.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1626" width="229" height="229"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A bus filled with members of FF&amp;P’s Los Angeles office trekked off to Desert X to check out the sprawling outdoor art biennial held in California’s Coachella Valley. The bus stopped at several site-specific installations scattered across the desert and Salton Sea.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The first installation was <em>Specter</em> by American artist Sterling Ruby. The fluorescent orange box contrasts the desert landscape while relating in scale to man-made elements often experienced in the desert, like a shipping container, train or RV.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1628,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/2-1024x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1628"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Next stop, <em>Dive-In</em>, by the Danish collective SUPERFLEX. Dive-In’s pink color is derived from Walter and Leonore Annenberg’s preferred palette, as seen in their coral-filled home at Sunnylands (where FF&amp;P designed the Sunnylands Visitor Center). The piece’s rough texture acknowledges the fossilized marine life that is scattered across the region and explores themes of global warming and rising water levels. The artists imagine that the piece may also be enjoyed by marine life when it is one day submerged by rising waters.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1629,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/INSIDEOUTSIDE.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1629"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"right","id":1630,"width":282,"height":282,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/1-3.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1630" width="282" height="282"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>After Dive-In, the bus unloaded at <em>A Point of View,</em> by Bogotá-born/Paris-based&nbsp;artist Ivan Argote. The composition of staircases overlooking the Salton Sea function as sundials. Engraved messages on the concrete steps depict fragmented messages that relate to the temporal fragmentation of the sundials.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Lastly, FF&amp;P experienced the digital work by Nancy Baker titled<em> Margin of Error</em>. This piece uses augmented reality to comment on “the toxic outcome of human progress leading to an environmental disaster” sited at the shrinking Salton Sea. The installations all bring attention to the valley's environment through careful siting and attention to user experience. The display of works by emerging artists all touch on global warming and how design can enact change.&nbsp;Freshly inspired by a long day of research, the bus departed the Salton Sea filled with inspiration to return to work at FF&amp;P!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2019-04-26 12:28:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1532</ID>
		<Title>Genius Loci</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:image {"align":"right","id":1616,"width":308,"height":233,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/AQJ_FF_0176.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1616" width="308" height="233"/><figcaption>Photography by: <a href="https://www.ba-reps.com/photographers/jason-schmidt">Jason Schmidt</a></figcaption></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Author: Summer Stuckey, Frederick Fisher and Partners</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>&nbsp;Genius loci speaks to specificity, the combination of tangible and intangible characteristics that make a place unique.&nbsp; We at FF&amp;P are lucky to work in a historic landmark designed by A. Quincy Jones for his own architecture practice. An environment loaded with personality, This timeless building inspires the creativity and domesticity that have become a signature part of our design ethos.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Here are a few of our favorite spaces and places within our office. One designer expressed her gratitude for the <em>Ray Q. Galano Memorial Garden</em>: “How many places can one work while hearing the ambient sound of gurgling water? &nbsp;The sound of the fountain while we design feels luxurious!” Another colleague noted two favorite aspects: &nbsp;the beautiful natural light that filters into the main studio through its big, double- height windows, and the serene view of the lush plants that fill our central courtyard. Soaking up the sun on cool days or savoring the breezes on warm ones, we are always happy to take advantage of our office’s strong sense of indoor/outdoor connection.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:gallery {"ids":[1619,1620,1621,1622,1623]} -->
<figure class="wp-block-gallery columns-3 is-cropped"><ul class="blocks-gallery-grid"><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/FFP-GalanoCourtyard1.jpg" alt="" data-id="1619" data-full-url="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/FFP-GalanoCourtyard1.jpg" data-link="https://fisherpartners.net/genius-loci/ffp-galanocourtyard1/" class="wp-image-1619"/></figure></li><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/FFP-GalanoCourtyard2.jpg" alt="" data-id="1620" data-full-url="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/FFP-GalanoCourtyard2.jpg" data-link="https://fisherpartners.net/genius-loci/ffp-galanocourtyard2/" class="wp-image-1620"/></figure></li><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/AQJ_FF_0042-1.jpg" alt="" data-id="1621" data-full-url="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/AQJ_FF_0042-1.jpg" data-link="https://fisherpartners.net/genius-loci/aqj_ff_0042-1/" class="wp-image-1621"/></figure></li><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/AQJ_FF_0071-1.jpg" alt="" data-id="1622" data-full-url="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/AQJ_FF_0071-1.jpg" data-link="https://fisherpartners.net/genius-loci/aqj_ff_0071-1/" class="wp-image-1622"/></figure></li><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/AQJ_FF_0165-1024x660.jpg" alt="" data-id="1623" data-full-url="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/AQJ_FF_0165.jpg" data-link="https://fisherpartners.net/genius-loci/aqj_ff_0165/" class="wp-image-1623"/></figure></li></ul></figure>
<!-- /wp:gallery -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Whether it’s the secret closet, the cozy study, the roof deck, or the Japanese-influenced rock garden, each corner of our office has a unique identity, and serves a different purpose. Together, however, they create an environment that evokes a real sense of belonging—to its geography, historic moment, and community.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2019-05-17 12:13:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1534</ID>
		<Title>Plastic Free July</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Author: Summer Stuckey, Frederick Fisher and Partners</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>If you get nostalgic about all those toys you played with and loved as a kid, there’s good news—most of them are still around.&nbsp; The bad news is why.&nbsp; With very few exceptions, every toothbrush, every takeout container, and every shampoo bottle we use is made of plastic. And plastic does not decompose.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:core-embed/vimeo {"url":"https://player.vimeo.com/video/340093330","type":"video","providerNameSlug":"vimeo","align":"right","className":"wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-embed-vimeo alignright wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-vimeo wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
https://player.vimeo.com/video/340093330
</div></figure>
<!-- /wp:core-embed/vimeo -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Plastic Free July is a global movement that aims to increase our awareness of plastic pollution and helps people take part in solving the problem. This year marks the second time that FF&amp;P has participated.&nbsp; To make it fun, we organized in-house activities like a plastic-free lunch competition.&nbsp; Another highlight was when FF&amp;P hosted a visit from <a href="https://www.refilleryla.com/">The Refillery LA</a>, a local BYOC (bring your own container) mobile company offering personal care, cleaning, and laundry products for you to take home in recycled glass jars.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>As we become more conscious of our decisions regarding the products we acquire for our office and personal use, we reinforce our firm’s commitment to improving our community and our planet.&nbsp; Although there is still a long way to go, every step counts.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2019-07-31 13:16:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1536</ID>
		<Title>Santa Monica City Service Building - AIA | LA 2019 COTE NEXT Honor Award Winner</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The most competitive and prestigious awards bestowed by the American Institute of Architects Los Angeles were announced last night at the 2019 AIA|LA Design Awards Ceremony + Party. Selected from hundreds of entries, winners were chosen by juries composed of leading figures and experts in the architectural world.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>“At a time when Los Angeles turns to its architects to address some our greatest challenges, these winning projects contribute to quality of life in Los Angeles and points beyond, through the realization of design excellence,” stated 2019 AIA|LA President Barbara Bouza, FAIA.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>“Winning entries represent work which seamlessly blend aesthetic and function to produce buildings that elevate design excellence,” continued Bouza. “They also demonstrate attainment of demanding sustain ability performance goals, and new means for architecture to fulfill city building.”</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2><strong>The City of Santa Monica City Services Building received the <br>2019 AIA | LA COTE NEXT Honor Award. </strong></h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":1612,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/180627_OLYMPICELEVATION_v2_web-1024x574.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1612"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"right","id":1613,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/AIALA_SMCSBHonor.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1613"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><em>The jurors commented on it’s smart and sophisticated water catchment and treatment systems in such an arid environment and how the glass facade opens the civic functions to the public, just as the City wishes them to be.<br>(Full project details </em><a href="https://fisherpartners.net/projects/city-of-santa-monica-city-services-building/"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><em>HERE</em></span></a><em>).</em></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The ceremony, which was followed by a party, took place at the Saban Media Center Wolf Theatre in North Hollywood and was presented by Sharpe Interior Systems, Inc. Six-hundred architects, designers, individuals from companies related to the field, and supporters of architecture gathered in the venue, which is located on the campus of the Television Academy.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>“The evening is an opportunity for the entire design community to come together,” said AIA|LA Executive Director Carlo Caccavale, Hon. AIA|LA. “We are not only celebrating design, but the process of realizing architecture and those who do so. Each year, in staging the Design Awards, our intention is to provide a backdrop that encourages camaraderie and connection.”</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In addition to the juried awards, Presidential Honorees, selected by Bouza and the 2019 AIA|LA Board of Directors and announced previously by the AIA|LA, were also celebrated. Among these was the winner of the 2019 AIA|LA Gold Medal, who received it posthumously, Norma Merrick Sklarek, FAIA. Sklarek becomes the first black woman to be presented with the medal. Though Sklarek passed away in 2012, her influence on the profession remains profound: through the buildings she oversaw—such as the Pacific Design Center’s Blue Whale, MOCA and Terminal One of Los Angeles International Airport—and as a mentor and inspiring figure to many.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>View the full list of winners:<br><a href="https://www.aialosangeles.org/awards/design-awards/cote-cote-next-winners-2019/?utm_campaign=Eblasts&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_source=2019%20Design%20Award%20Winners%20Announced%20by%20AIA%7CLA"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">COTE LA/COTE NEXT Awards Winners</span></a><br><a href="https://www.aialosangeles.org/awards/design-awards/next-la-winners-2019/?utm_campaign=Eblasts&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_source=2019%20Design%20Award%20Winners%20Announced%20by%20AIA%7CLA"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">NEXT LA Awards Winners</span></a><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><br></span><a href="https://www.aialosangeles.org/awards/design-awards/da-winners-2019/"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Design Awards Winners</span></a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:separator -->
<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>
<!-- /wp:separator -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The AIA|LA Design Awards program consider and award entries in four separate categories: AIA|LA Design Awards, NEXT LA awards, AIA|LA COTE (AIA|LA Committee for the Environment) and AIA|LA COTE NEXT. The first, the namesake AIA|LA Design Awards, recognizes the design excellence of some of the most significant completed projects in the country at this time. Unbuilt or are still-to-be-completed-commissions are considered and awarded through the AIA|LA Next LA awards program. AIA|LA COTE (Committee for the Environment, AIA|LA) Award recipients are bestowed for demonstrable achievement in sustainable design and acknowledged for performance, systems integration and other such components. COTE NEXT awards recognize COTE projects that are as yet unbuilt.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Completed projects, located anywhere, that are designed by AIA members&nbsp;from firms based in the Los Angeles area, and architecture constructed in Los&nbsp;Angeles by any AIA member, no matter their base of operations, are&nbsp;eligible for submission for Design Awards entry.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><em>This text excerpt courtesy of the AIA | LA.<br>Tibby Rothman, Hon. AIA|LA<br>Director, Marketing and Public Relations<br>p: 213-639-0763, e:</em><a href="mailto:tibby@aialosangeles.org"><em>tibby@aialosangeles.org</em></a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>View full AIA | LA Press Release <a href="To view the entire slate of entries to all 2019 AIA|LA Design Awards categories, visit: https://www.aialosangeles.org/news/press-releases/design-award-winners-for-2019-announced-by-aiala/?utm_source=2019+Design+Award+Winners+Announced+by+AIA%7CLA&amp;utm_campaign=Eblasts&amp;utm_medium=email"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">HERE</span></a>.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2019-10-29 10:50:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1538</ID>
		<Title>Ecologically Aware</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:image {"align":"right","id":1609,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/1-2.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1609"/><figcaption>The Kendeda Building at Georgia Tech</figcaption></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Author: Summer Stuckey, Frederick Fisher and Partners</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>FF&amp;P is committed to improving lives through architecture. One way we ensure to evolve and build a sustainable future is by advocating for the marketplace to change through material choices. As a firm with multiple LEED projects ranging from silver, platinum, and our country’s first municipal Living Building Challenge in Santa Monica, CA. We are striving to educate ourselves for a better future for all.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>We recently attended Greenbuild, the largest annual event for green building professionals worldwide. The event focused on cutting edge solutions to improve resilience, sustainability, and quality of life in our buildings, cities, and communities.&nbsp; The conference ignites relationships and inspires knowledge amongst leaders and cultivates the next generation of standards, policies, and collaborations to ensure the promise of a higher living standard into a reality for all.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Author: Summer Stuckey, Frederick Fisher and Partners</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2019-12-04 08:11:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1540</ID>
		<Title>Frieze LA: Art and Architecture with Frederick Fisher and Partners</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A guided tour led by Fred Fisher and the FF&amp;P design team was held on Wednesday, February 12th. VIP Guests were brought through the home envisioned as a piece of art itself.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"right","id":1602,"width":315,"height":236,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><img class="wp-image-1602" src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/FFP_LightHouse_50S9709-1.jpg" alt="" width="315" height="236" />
<figcaption>Photography by: Joe Fletcher</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In Los Angeles, it is easy to feel disconnected from the living world, but this Mandeville Canyon residence by Frederick Fisher and Partners is designed to act as a walk-through garden. The garden was designed with the fives senses in-mind; sight, hearing, smell, taste, and touch.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The home was strategically designed to frame views to the outdoors. With a lifetime’s collection of museum-worthy paintings, sculptures, and furniture from leading contemporary artists and designers including David Hockney, Enrique Martinez Celaya, Joe Goode and Ed Moses, among others. The residential tour was the perfect showcase for Frieze LA: Art and Architecture with Frederick Fisher and Partners.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2020-02-27 14:55:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1542</ID>
		<Title>Earth Day: Virtual Tour Introducing the Santa Monica City Hall East</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>To coincide with Earth Day, FF&amp;P along with The City of Santa Monica, engineering firm Buro Happold and Hathaway Dinwiddie Construction Company, are participating in a virtual tour today of the new City Hall East to members of the design, civic and cultural community in lieu of the public grand opening originally scheduled.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Brought on by the city to design a building that consolidates all of its municipal departments in a single location, the 50,2000 square foot building situated behind the Historic 1939 Parkinson and Estep-designed City Hall is intended to be a model of ecological resilience and self-sufficiency by producing more energy than it uses and zero waste generation.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"right","id":1593,"width":362,"height":272,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/10_IMG_8239.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1593" width="362" height="272"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This involved surpassing LEED criteria and achieving the <a href="https://living-future.org/lbc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Living Building Challenge</a> requirements set by the International Living Future Institute–the world’s most rigorous and comprehensive green building standard. To achieve these standards, we set out to design a building that follows passive solar principles with numerous energy-saving and producing systems, such as a series of photovoltaic arrays totaling nearly 15,000 square feet, the most composting toilets of any municipal building in the United States, and the first civic rainwater recycling system in California to convert rain to potable water on site.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"left","id":1594,"width":336,"height":229,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/Retouched6P8A69764x6.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1594" width="336" height="229"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>We converted the adjacent land into a comprehensive civic campus that benefits both city workers and the public, while respecting the architectural prominence of the historically landmarked art deco City Hall. The new building’s exterior glass envelope symbolizes Santa Monica’s civic commitment to transparency in serving the public while reflecting the light conditions of the sky as it changes throughout the day. Inside, a variety of open workspaces, meeting, and collaboration areas promote spontaneous interaction, while smaller huddle rooms allow for individual privacy when needed. The courtyard, which connects the new building to the historic City Hall, offers additional work and leisure areas with trees and other flora that generate shade, assist with cooling and insulation, and provide edible herbs and produce for building workers and local shelters.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>We are proud to be a part of this environmental initiative that reflects our own commitment to improving lives through architecture–increasing the quality of life for employees working in Santa Monica City Hall, City Hall East, and residents alike. Together we are building a better future for human and environmental health.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://fisherpartners.net/projects/city-of-santa-monica-city-services-building/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Read More</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Visit <a href="https://usgbc-la.org/event-details/3434/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">USGBCLA</a> to register for the virtual tour.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Watch the Santa Monica City Services Building film produced by Buro Happold. Credits: Buro Happold: MEP engineer, facades, lighting, sustainability, and living building consultant. Video: Prismedia LLC</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:core-embed/vimeo {"url":"https://player.vimeo.com/video/387241026","type":"video","providerNameSlug":"vimeo","className":"wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-embed-vimeo wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-vimeo wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
https://player.vimeo.com/video/387241026
</div></figure>
<!-- /wp:core-embed/vimeo -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2020-04-22 08:25:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1544</ID>
		<Title>“Delight is one of our prime motivations for practicing architecture.” – Frederick Fisher</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>We took the time to reflect on what still brings us delight in the world today - whether it is something handmade, read, or experienced. During one of our weekly staff meetings, we shared personal photos, books, food, nature, music, art, poetry, illustrations, etc. that reflects our inspiration. Not only was this uplifting, but we learned something more about one another which brought us closer together as a group while working remotely from home.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"left","id":1585,"width":195,"height":285,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/Spring.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1585" width="195" height="285"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>By continuing to educate ourselves through art, literature, history, and philosophy we allow ourselves to evolve as designers and architects. Our delight creates an open dialog between us as we discover new ways to improve the lives of people, communities, and organizations in the world around us. We are united not only by the projects we design, but as thinkers, and collaborators.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>At FF&amp;P we remain creative, and curious while looking forward to envisioning a better future for everyone. From a window view to a box of lemons to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/04/29/arts/music/brian-eno-ambient-songs.html?smid=nytcore-ios-share" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ambient music</a>, the following pieces are just a glimpse of what motivates us at FF&amp;P with every project we work on and new opportunity that presents itself.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:html -->
<div style="padding:56.25% 0 0 0;position:relative;clear:both"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/420355983?title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div><script src="https://player.vimeo.com/api/player.js"></script>
<!-- /wp:html -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2020-05-20 09:00:16</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1771</ID>
		<Title>Returning to the Office - The New Normal</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:image {"align":"left","id":1777,"width":288,"height":288} -->
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignleft is-resized"><img class="wp-image-1777 alignleft" src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/IMG_6504_Jake-1024x1024.jpg" alt="" width="250" height="250" /></figure>
</div>
<!-- /wp:image -->
<p style="text-align: left;">We are making plans to return to the office by redefining our workplace to ensure our health and wellbeing. This entails monitoring the number of people in the office on any given day, social distancing, following all CDC cleaning guidelines, and recreating a place that is as safe as it is creative.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: inherit;">After spending the last few months working from home apart from our friends and colleagues, many of us are asking ourselves, “what will it be like returning to the office?”  Our daily routines, including our 10am and 2pm coffee walks to the corner shop will have to be rethought and our full office breakfast meetings, BBQ lunches, and 3pm ice cream taste-test challenges will be postponed or greatly reduced in number of attendees. </span><span style="font-size: inherit;">While necessary right now, this is still a big change in our “normal” work life and will require time to refamiliarize ourselves as we adjust. We are embracing the challenges brought forth and exploring the limitless possibilities this “rethink” is allowing us in our personal lives, our work lives, and our clients’ lives.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">As we embrace our “new normal,” we are all looking forward to reuniting with our colleagues and returning to our habitual work/ life balance. Take a glimpse as to what we are looking forward to the most when we return - from having design workshops in-person again, to a sunset view from our NYC studio, to watching the leaves of the Ginkgo tree in the garden of our LA studio burst into color, these are some of our favorite moments from the past.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"> <iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/430781807" width="640" height="564" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>]]></Content>
		<Date>2020-07-13 18:31:12</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1862</ID>
		<Title>A Look Inside: Designing the Santa Monica City Hall East Building</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>FF&amp;P worked with the City of Santa Monica to lead the design for the Santa Monica City Hall East building which opened on Earth Day 2020. The City aimed to consolidate its workforce that had been scattered in separate properties into one cohesive workspace connected to its historic Civic Center. FF&amp;P, the City, and the rest of the design team achieved this through the addition of more than 50,000 square feet of open, interactive workspace connected directly to the historic City Hall that reflects a combination of our design ethos and the unique identity of the City of Santa Monica.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"right","id":1874,"width":360,"height":223,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/SMCS-02-1024x636.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1874" width="360" height="223"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The original footprint for the 1939 City Hall was a major driver in the planning of City Hall East as an addition to the existing structure. FF&amp;P sought to create a modern, forward-thinking atmosphere, while remaining sensitive to the historical and architectural context of the site. This addition, combined with the footprint of the original building, created a new central courtyard. This common outdoor space became the central focal point of the project and helped us define two distinct zones for the building interior: the Workspace Courtyard and the Shadow Space.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"left","id":1864,"width":355,"height":183,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-large is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/20-0617-SMCS-INTERIORS-1024x528.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1864" width="355" height="183"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The Workspace Courtyard is made up of individual and private workspaces for city employees to connect to the outdoors – infusing the natural elements into the space with operable windows for cross ventilation and natural light. In this way, we sought to blur the line between inside and outside and make the building’s open workspace an extension of the new central courtyard. The Shadow Space refers to the area in the new addition that sits in the shadow of the historic City Hall building. This was programmed with communal meeting and collaboration spaces. To make them more familiar and comfortable for the employees, the Shadow Space has a spirit of domesticity that is a hallmark of FF&amp;P’s design ethos. The break areas feature comfortable furniture, artwork, and natural light, giving employees a place to feel at home while collaborating with each other.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Resilience and sustainability were key drivers for the entire City Hall East project. This 52,000 square foot building is the largest civic building of this size and density in the world to be designed to achieve the<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://living-future.org/lbc/" target="_blank"> Living Building Challenge</a>, the world’s most rigorous and comprehensive green building standard–producing more energy that it uses and generating zero waste. Resilience and sustainability were incorporated in the building’s interior materials and informed the look and feel of the entire design, including the interior finish palette that reflects the beauty of the City’s natural beach setting. We are proud of this environmental initiative that allowed us to combine our own passion for improving life through architecture with the City’s mission of fostering collaboration and innovation.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2020-07-29 18:46:08</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1928</ID>
		<Title>Creating an Open Dialogue</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>As current events unfold, FF&amp;P is further encouraging our office culture of maintaining an open dialogue with one another to better educate ourselves and each other. This strengthens our environment of safety and sense of belonging. Early on, one of our colleagues held a public forum on how we were processing recent world events and how we could better help each other as a team. We have continued this conversation by dedicating a segment of our weekly staff meetings for us to talk openly about issues in the built environment influenced by art, education, politics, and culture. Each week, we focus on a different topic encouraging everyone to share relevant photos, links, and videos - many that are historical in context with personal meaning to our designers.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"center","id":1931,"width":391,"height":178} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/Joseph-Eichler-Home-600x273.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1931" width="391" height="178"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>During one of these sessions, we were reminded of Joseph Eichler who was synonymous for the mid-century modern style tract housing in California who fought for fair housing policies and integrated neighborhoods. His aim was to construct inclusive and diverse planned communities and he established a non-discrimination policy, offering homes for sale to anyone of any race or religion.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"center","id":1932,"width":375,"height":268} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter is-resized"><img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/losangeles-residential-security-map-600x430.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1932" width="375" height="268"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"left"} -->
<p class="has-text-align-left">While researching the Silver Lake area, there was a history of exclusion preventing African-Americans from buying homes throughout the area. The Federal Housing Administration, created in 1934, subsidized builders who were creating entire subdivisions on the premise that they only be sold to whites. If a home builder so much as assisted a Black buyer in purchasing a house, they would lose funding for an entire tract. Furthermore, the FHA refused to unsure mortgages in and near African-American neighborhoods, which were outlined as “redlined” neighborhoods, a practice that has defined the built environment of countless American cities. As designers, we must think of what it means to create a more equitable built environment, and a step in the right direction happens in conversation and education.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>As we learn from the past, we strive to build a better future to improve the well-being of everyone in every community. Members of our design team participate in <a href="https://socalnoma.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SoCal NOMA’s</a> annual project pipeline community outreach initiative– teaching kids in under-resourced areas about architecture and urban planning. We ask ourselves what else we can improve upon as architects and designers dedicated to bettering the field for future generations by coming together to create more vibrant, equitable and inclusive communities. We seek to do more by working together to help change current systems, continuing to volunteer and partake in improving the world around us. At the very least, promoting an open conversation about how we can design for a more equitable future is necessary and something we do every week.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2020-09-01 23:10:27</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>1969</ID>
		<Title>White Paper: Designing for Togetherness</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:shortcode -->
<p>[wpdm_package id='1967']</p>
<!-- /wp:shortcode -->

<!-- wp:file {"id":2269,"href":"https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/Designing-for-Togetherness_v6_spreads.pdf"} -->
<div class="wp-block-file"><a href="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/Designing-for-Togetherness_v6_spreads.pdf">Designing for Togetherness_v6_spreads</a><a href="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/Designing-for-Togetherness_v6_spreads.pdf" class="wp-block-file__button" download>Download</a></div>
<!-- /wp:file -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2020-10-14 06:25:33</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>2000</ID>
		<Title>White Paper: Reconsidering the Restroom</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:file {"id":2270,"href":"https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/180617-Reconsidering-the-Restroom-Spreads.pdf"} -->
<div class="wp-block-file"><a href="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/180617-Reconsidering-the-Restroom-Spreads.pdf">180617 - Reconsidering the Restroom - Spreads</a><a href="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/180617-Reconsidering-the-Restroom-Spreads.pdf" class="wp-block-file__button" download>Download</a></div>
<!-- /wp:file -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></Content>
		<Date>2020-10-19 23:38:06</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>2080</ID>
		<Title>Designing for Togetherness: Safe Environments for Connecting during C-19</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[For the past few months, we at FF&amp;P have been working with our clients and within our own office to understand best space design practices for returning safely to our respective workplaces, academic and cultural campuses, etc. during this time of the coronavirus pandemic. In the spirit of trying to help as many people as possible, we wanted to share some lessons learned thus far.

Given that global understanding of the science behind C-19’s spread and containment continues to evolve, we started from the standpoint that there is no absolute “right” way to handle this situation, either scientifically or in terms of design. As such, we are exploring the issue the same way we approach all our projects: outside-in and inside-out. From the outside-in, we are conducting thorough research, considering multiple perspectives and information sources ranging from trusted medical and public health organizations and professionals, to mechanical engineers, to furniture manufacturers. In parallel, we are seeking to understand our clients’ institutional and organizational missions, existing spatial conditions, user groups and their daily operations, as well as their needs, desires, and cultures.

We do not claim to be experts in pandemic safety, and we do not advocate one set of best practices over another. Rather, we are simply taking proactive steps to help our clients and ourselves consider the issue from all angles, ask smart questions, identify available operational scenarios, and propose individually feasible strategies for implementation.

Our goal in this work is to ensure that we and our clients feel informed and empowered to make decisions that are both safe and appropriate for each of us. To read more, and download the PDF White Paper <span style="color: #3366ff;"><a style="color: #3366ff;" href="https://fisherpartners.net/categories/white-papers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">click here</a></span><span style="color: #000000;">.</span>

&nbsp;]]></Content>
		<Date>1970-01-01 00:00:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>2086</ID>
		<Title>Reconsidering the Restroom Opportunities of the Single Stall Public Restroom</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[Meandering along the curving paths nestled into the hills of Santa Monica’s Tongva Park (FIGURE 2), designed by James Corner Field Operations with Frederick Fisher and Partners Architects, one encounters various garden ‘eddies’ within the landscape. While most offer moments of serenity and pause, one of these opens into a wide passage connecting one path to another under a landscaped hill (FIGURE 1). This is Tongva Park’s public restroom—an eighteen-foot-wide by forty-foot-long breezeway flanked by toilet partitions and a trough sink on each side. Though a partial-height, wooden screen divides the ‘comfort station’ into two areas, little beyond door signage and color divides this space.

The Tongva Park restroom is one of several single stall public restrooms that Frederick Fisher and Partners (FF&amp;P) has recently completed. Single stall restrooms are a group of individual toilet compartments available to all users, regardless of gender, with sinks either inside them or in common handwashing areas (FIGURE 4). Each of these projects explores the opportunities of single stall restrooms as an alternative to conventional sex-specific, multi-user restrooms.

To read more, and download the PDF White Paper <span style="color: #3366ff;"><a style="color: #3366ff;" href="https://fisherpartners.net/categories/white-papers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">click here</a></span><span style="color: #000000;">.</span>

&nbsp;]]></Content>
		<Date>1970-01-01 00:00:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>2374</ID>
		<Title>A Look Inside: Ojai Valley School</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[<div id="block-81fed41e90a89b2b6a11" class="sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html" data-block-type="2">
<div class="sqs-block-content">
<p class="">In 2017, the Thomas Fire swept through the core campus of the Ojai Valley School (OVS) in Ojai California, destroying everything in its path. Even though the losses were significant, the fire created an opportunity for a new “blank slate.”</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1632862855325_31172" class="sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image sqs-col-6 span-6 float float-right sqs-text-ready" data-block-type="5">
<div id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_69" class="sqs-block-content">
<div id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_68" class="image-block-outer-wrapper
          layout-caption-below
          design-layout-inline
          combination-animation-none
          individual-animation-none
          individual-text-animation-none
         sqs-narrow-width" data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">
<figure id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_67" class="
              sqs-block-image-figure
              intrinsic
            ">
<div id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_66" class="image-block-wrapper" data-animation-role="image">
<div id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_65" class="sqs-image-shape-container-element

              has-aspect-ratio
            "><img class="thumb-image loaded" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5ab536b77c9327e5eed2d6fc/1632863287900-KHV9ME050JIXBDF25MR5/OVS+Top+of+Hill-by+Misty+Hall_40.jpg?format=300w" alt="OVS Top of Hill-by Misty Hall_40.jpg" data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5ab536b77c9327e5eed2d6fc/1632863287900-KHV9ME050JIXBDF25MR5/OVS+Top+of+Hill-by+Misty+Hall_40.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5ab536b77c9327e5eed2d6fc/1632863287900-KHV9ME050JIXBDF25MR5/OVS+Top+of+Hill-by+Misty+Hall_40.jpg" data-image-dimensions="5004x3336" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" data-load="false" data-image-id="6153842fafa3484b95c0b091" data-type="image" data-image-resolution="300w" /></div>
</div></figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1632874612491_43251" class="sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html" data-block-type="2">
<div class="sqs-block-content">
<p class="">We recently wrapped up work on a new complex for Ojai Valley School– just in time to welcome students back to campus! Our work on the project began in 2015 with a collaborative and comprehensive visioning and master planning exercise with the Ojai Valley School community to help articulate and clarify the Upper School’s short and long-term programmatic needs while combining their philosophical ideals with site integration, functionality, and an aesthetic of inspiration.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1632874612491_39965" class="sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image sqs-col-6 span-6 float float-left sqs-text-ready" data-block-type="5">
<div id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_94" class="sqs-block-content">
<div id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_93" class="image-block-outer-wrapper
          layout-caption-below
          design-layout-inline
          combination-animation-none
          individual-animation-none
          individual-text-animation-none
         sqs-narrow-width" data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">
<figure id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_92" class="
              sqs-block-image-figure
              intrinsic
            ">
<div id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_91" class="image-block-wrapper" data-animation-role="image">
<div id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_90" class="sqs-image-shape-container-element

              has-aspect-ratio
            "><img class="thumb-image loaded" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5ab536b77c9327e5eed2d6fc/1632875183394-ZRWN1A06GZ6FJPY0LST8/OVS+Top+of+Hill-by+Misty+Hall_36.jpg?format=500w" alt="OVS Top of Hill-by Misty Hall_36.jpg" data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5ab536b77c9327e5eed2d6fc/1632875183394-ZRWN1A06GZ6FJPY0LST8/OVS+Top+of+Hill-by+Misty+Hall_36.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5ab536b77c9327e5eed2d6fc/1632875183394-ZRWN1A06GZ6FJPY0LST8/OVS+Top+of+Hill-by+Misty+Hall_36.jpg" data-image-dimensions="5039x3360" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" data-load="false" data-image-id="6153b2a9bed94f66b9c39192" data-type="image" data-image-resolution="500w" /></div>
</div></figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1632874612491_44415" class="sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html" data-block-type="2">
<div class="sqs-block-content">
<p class="">The Thomas Fire prompted an immediate need to replace the lost buildings on the 195-acre site overlooking the Ojai Valley in Ventura County. The OVS Upper Campus includes the three new permanent structures - the Aramont Science and Technology Center, the Grace Hobson Smith House Dormitory, and the Littlefield Student Commons dining and library complex.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1632874612491_16164" class="sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image sqs-col-6 span-6 float float-right sqs-text-ready" data-block-type="5">
<div id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_112" class="sqs-block-content">
<div id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_111" class="image-block-outer-wrapper
          layout-caption-below
          design-layout-inline
          combination-animation-none
          individual-animation-none
          individual-text-animation-none
         sqs-narrow-width" data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">
<figure id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_110" class="
              sqs-block-image-figure
              intrinsic
            ">
<div id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_109" class="image-block-wrapper" data-animation-role="image">
<div id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_108" class="sqs-image-shape-container-element

              has-aspect-ratio
            "><img class="thumb-image loaded" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5ab536b77c9327e5eed2d6fc/1632874700779-UBU4ZFIZEYKJGFY5YBWS/OVS+Top+of+Hill-by+Misty+Hall_31.jpg?format=500w" alt="OVS Top of Hill-by Misty Hall_31.jpg" data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5ab536b77c9327e5eed2d6fc/1632874700779-UBU4ZFIZEYKJGFY5YBWS/OVS+Top+of+Hill-by+Misty+Hall_31.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5ab536b77c9327e5eed2d6fc/1632874700779-UBU4ZFIZEYKJGFY5YBWS/OVS+Top+of+Hill-by+Misty+Hall_31.jpg" data-image-dimensions="5083x3389" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" data-load="false" data-image-id="6153b0c37ca0d762e239fb68" data-type="image" data-image-resolution="500w" /></div>
</div></figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1632874612491_18103" class="sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html" data-block-type="2">
<div class="sqs-block-content">
<p class="">The three new buildings respect the existing campus architecture while forming a village of minimal pavilions that connect the dynamic functions of learning, studying, and student living. Each building has adjacent outdoor space for learning and gathering. The 3 buildings all together create a plaza. One is either in the building, or in the outdoor space and with a view to nature which is always part of the experience.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1632874612491_21787" class="sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image sqs-col-6 span-6 float float-left sqs-text-ready" data-block-type="5">
<div id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_130" class="sqs-block-content">
<div id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_129" class="image-block-outer-wrapper
          layout-caption-below
          design-layout-inline
          combination-animation-none
          individual-animation-none
          individual-text-animation-none
         sqs-narrow-width" data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">
<figure id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_128" class="
              sqs-block-image-figure
              intrinsic
            ">
<div id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_127" class="image-block-wrapper" data-animation-role="image">
<div id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_126" class="sqs-image-shape-container-element

              has-aspect-ratio
            "><img class="thumb-image loaded" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5ab536b77c9327e5eed2d6fc/1632874855769-MX6TP33F5JN807XRISPL/OVS+Top+of+Hill-by+Misty+Hall_48.jpg?format=500w" alt="OVS Top of Hill-by Misty Hall_48.jpg" data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5ab536b77c9327e5eed2d6fc/1632874855769-MX6TP33F5JN807XRISPL/OVS+Top+of+Hill-by+Misty+Hall_48.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5ab536b77c9327e5eed2d6fc/1632874855769-MX6TP33F5JN807XRISPL/OVS+Top+of+Hill-by+Misty+Hall_48.jpg" data-image-dimensions="4960x3307" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" data-load="false" data-image-id="6153b160da614a46180f0b9f" data-type="image" data-image-resolution="500w" /></div>
</div></figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1632874612491_23417" class="sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html" data-block-type="2">
<div class="sqs-block-content">
<p class="">Our desire was to weave a sense of Discovery throughout the entire. A thoughtfully positioned terrace, provides breathtaking views of pink sunset covered mountains. Breezeways usher in wind from the valley. A tree in the dorm area courtyard, serves a symbolic reminder of changing seasons. Key moments of Discovery, meant to honor a one-of-a-kind space.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1632855580399_22993" class="sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image sqs-col-6 span-6 float float-right sqs-text-ready" data-block-type="5">
<div id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_148" class="sqs-block-content">
<div id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_147" class="image-block-outer-wrapper
          layout-caption-below
          design-layout-inline
          combination-animation-none
          individual-animation-none
          individual-text-animation-none
         sqs-narrow-width" data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">
<figure id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_146" class="
              sqs-block-image-figure
              intrinsic
            ">
<div id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_145" class="image-block-wrapper" data-animation-role="image">
<div id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_144" class="sqs-image-shape-container-element

              has-aspect-ratio
            "><img class="thumb-image loaded" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5ab536b77c9327e5eed2d6fc/1632860881538-15583ACPD0ND051BIW2C/IMG_1291.jpg?format=500w" alt="IMG_1291.jpg" data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5ab536b77c9327e5eed2d6fc/1632860881538-15583ACPD0ND051BIW2C/IMG_1291.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5ab536b77c9327e5eed2d6fc/1632860881538-15583ACPD0ND051BIW2C/IMG_1291.jpg" data-image-dimensions="1536x956" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" data-load="false" data-image-id="61537ad1535266529b9be089" data-type="image" data-image-resolution="500w" /></div>
</div></figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1632874612491_20736" class="sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html" data-block-type="2">
<div class="sqs-block-content">
<p class="">While the design language is simple, experience throughout the project is diverse. We intended to create diverse experiences utilizing the form of boxes. Together, these seemingly “static” boxes create a sense of dynamism through the unique dialogue in the space between them. With the addition of recessed doors and windows, this collection of “mass” begins to feel like a cohesive entity. The new design is intended to be a complement to the existing campus character but not mimicking it - timeless and experience-driven.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1632855580399_62807" class="sqs-block image-block sqs-block-image sqs-col-6 span-6 float float-left sqs-text-ready" data-block-type="5">
<div id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_166" class="sqs-block-content">
<div id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_165" class="image-block-outer-wrapper
          layout-caption-below
          design-layout-inline
          combination-animation-none
          individual-animation-none
          individual-text-animation-none
         sqs-narrow-width" data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">
<figure id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_164" class="
              sqs-block-image-figure
              intrinsic
            ">
<div id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_163" class="image-block-wrapper" data-animation-role="image">
<div id="yui_3_17_2_1_1634321926489_162" class="sqs-image-shape-container-element

              has-aspect-ratio
            "><img class="thumb-image loaded" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5ab536b77c9327e5eed2d6fc/1632861786895-S4VEXOCOKUXL0Y168G23/OVS_FFP_ProjectExterior2.jpg?format=500w" alt="OVS_FFP_ProjectExterior2.jpg" data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5ab536b77c9327e5eed2d6fc/1632861786895-S4VEXOCOKUXL0Y168G23/OVS_FFP_ProjectExterior2.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5ab536b77c9327e5eed2d6fc/1632861786895-S4VEXOCOKUXL0Y168G23/OVS_FFP_ProjectExterior2.jpg" data-image-dimensions="5464x3640" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" data-load="false" data-image-id="61537e4a1b50791678fdc213" data-type="image" data-image-resolution="500w" /></div>
</div></figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1632874612491_42129" class="sqs-block html-block sqs-block-html" data-block-type="2">
<div class="sqs-block-content">
<p class="">The design embraces the scenic landscape while reflecting the kinds of resiliency practices necessary to responsibly inhabit the area with use of passive cooling design, photoelectric power generation and a lithium-ion battery storage system that dramatically reduces CO2 emissions and allow the campus to operate off-grid. The site has been extensively fireproofed through the incorporation of flat roofs without eaves, stucco finishes, enhanced sprinklers and improved site access.</p>
<p class="">The Ojai Valley School reflects our own design ethos of improving life through architecture and sharing a common approach by connecting people to their environments and to each other.</p>

</div>
</div>]]></Content>
		<Date>2021-10-15 18:20:56</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>2549</ID>
		<Title>A Look Inside: Ojai Valley School</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[In 2017, the Thomas Fire swept through the core campus of the Ojai Valley School (OVS) in Ojai California, destroying everything in its path. Even though the losses were significant, the fire created an opportunity for a new “blank slate.”

We recently wrapped up work on a new complex for Ojai Valley School– just in time to welcome students back to campus! Our work on the project began in 2015 with a collaborative and comprehensive visioning and master planning exercise with the Ojai Valley School community to help articulate and clarify the Upper School’s short and long-term programmatic needs while combining their philosophical ideals with site integration, functionality, and an aesthetic of inspiration.


The Thomas Fire prompted an immediate need to replace the lost buildings on the 195-acre site overlooking the Ojai Valley in Ventura County. The OVS Upper Campus includes the three new permanent structures - the Aramont Science and Technology Center, the Grace Hobson Smith House Dormitory, and the Littlefield Student Commons dining and library complex.  


The three new buildings respect the existing campus architecture while forming a village of minimal pavilions that connect the dynamic functions of learning, studying, and student living. Each building has adjacent outdoor space for learning and gathering. The 3 buildings all together create a plaza. One is either in the building, or in the outdoor space and with a view to nature which is always part of the experience. 


Our desire was to weave a sense of Discovery throughout the entire. A thoughtfully positioned terrace, provides breathtaking views of pink sunset covered mountains. Breezeways usher in wind from the valley. A tree in the dorm area courtyard, serves a symbolic reminder of changing seasons. Key moments of Discovery, meant to honor a one-of-a-kind space. 


While the design language is simple, experience throughout the project is diverse. We intended to create diverse experiences utilizing the form of boxes. Together, these seemingly “static” boxes create a sense of dynamism through the unique dialogue in the space between them. With the addition of recessed doors and windows, this collection of “mass” begins to feel like a cohesive entity. The new design is intended to be a complement to the existing campus character but not mimicking it - timeless and experience-driven.

<img src="https://fisherpartners.net/wp-content/uploads/ALEX_NYE_211112_OVS_032-A-600x434.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="434" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2546" />
The design embraces the scenic landscape while reflecting the kinds of resiliency practices necessary to responsibly inhabit the area with use of passive cooling design, photoelectric power generation and a lithium-ion battery storage system that dramatically reduces CO2 emissions and allow the campus to operate off-grid. The site has been extensively fireproofed through the incorporation of flat roofs without eaves, stucco finishes, enhanced sprinklers and improved site access. 

The Ojai Valley School reflects our own design ethos of improving life through architecture and sharing a common approach by connecting people to their environments and to each other.]]></Content>
		<Date>1970-01-01 00:00:00</Date>
	</post>
	<post>
		<ID>2551</ID>
		<Title>Designing The Armory Show</Title>
		<Content><![CDATA[Established in 1994, The Armory Show is one of the world’s most galvanizing art shows, and the official kick-off to New York’s fall art season. The show presents the world’s leading international galleries showcasing works of art from both modern and contemporary artists while making art more accessible to the public as well as buyers, sellers and collectors. This was the first time in 17 years that the art fair was integrated under one roof. Having moved to the newly expanded Javits Center during the Covid-19 Pandemic, the show needed to be adapted to a new environment, to maximize the space’s benefits and comply with safety mandates. 

In 2021, Frederick Fisher and Partners was invited to reimagine the Armory Show in New York City’s Javits Center. As a collaborative design practice, FF&P worked closely with the show’s leadership to honor the art fair’s rich history, accommodate its ambitious expansion into a vast new location, and address the unique challenges presented by the COVID-19 pandemic. Inspired by the energy and spirit of the Armory Show’s host city, FF&P’s design succeeded in elevating the modern art fair environment into a varied, user-friendly experience infused with delight and enhancing the visitor in-person experience.

The open floor plan spanned three halls with unobstructed sightlines and spacious lounges. The concept of the design reflected the identity and energy of New York City. This was achieved by combining the intensity of a dense urban grid with an iconic, open public space that disrupted the regularity and introduced serendipitous encounters, much like Central Park and the Highline. 

The central space was conceived as an agora which spans the large Javits Center halls and connected its far corners while unifying the experience of the space. New York’s parks and rivers, landscape elements, pattern and color helped define the interior spaces.  The floor surfaces of the agora referenced the colors and textures of the nearby Highline and Hudson River. Visitors entered the fair through a bosque of trees that created a welcoming threshold and a more intimate, human sense of scale within the massive conference center. 

Our client, as well as the press, were vocally enthusiastic about the show’s design success—they felt it offered a striking yet complementary backdrop for the exhibiting galleries. 

“This is the start of a new chapter for the Armory Show. This is an opportunity to take this fair to the next level. The fair’s new layout, by Frederick Fisher and Partners, is allowing the art to shine.”  –  Nicole Berry,  Executive Director - The Armory Show]]></Content>
		<Date>1970-01-01 00:00:00</Date>
	</post>
</data>